<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://getpolarized.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://getpolarized.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-10-07T13:52:28-07:00</updated><id>https://getpolarized.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">POLAR - Easily manage your PDFs, web content, and notes.</title><subtitle>A powerful document manager for Mac, Windows, and Linux for managing web content, books, and notes and supports tagging, annotation, highlighting and keeps track of your reading progress.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Roger Craig used Polar to Win Jeopardy.</title><link href="https://getpolarized.io/2019/10/06/Roger-Craig-Uses-Polar-Jeopardy.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Roger Craig used Polar to Win Jeopardy." /><published>2019-10-06T09:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-10-06T09:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://getpolarized.io/2019/10/06/Roger-Craig-Uses-Polar-Jeopardy</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://getpolarized.io/2019/10/06/Roger-Craig-Uses-Polar-Jeopardy.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/lkRjAkq.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;roger-craig-used-polar-to-win-jeopardy&quot;&gt;Roger Craig used Polar to Win Jeopardy.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Polar has been rapidly adopted by alpha-geeks to combat information overload and looks like we’ve found another convert - 
this time &lt;a href=&quot;https://superorganizers.substack.com/p/how-a-jeopardy-champion-remembers&quot;&gt;Roger Craig who used it to win $77k on Jeopardy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;He’s a machine learning, data science, and AI practitioner who combined his computer skills and an interest in quiz
games into something extraordinarily unique:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;He won more than half a million dollars on Jeopardy!, including a whopping $77,000 in a single day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;He did this not just with raw intelligence, but by creating a system to help him fashion himself into a game-show
superstar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Roger and I have similar backgrounds - both machine learning and big data and it looks like we arrived at the same
general strategy for managing knowledge.  Specifically, use tools like NLP, clustering, and spaced repetition to force
material to be stored in your brain long term with high retention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;How he uses Polarized to save and take notes on PDFs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The next tool I use is called Polarized. A lot of the information I consume is in technical published papers, which are in PDFs, and Polarized helps with that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It takes in PDFs and web pages, and allows you to highlight and annotate them. You can also export them, so you can turn the annotations into Anki cards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;So basically every paper that is of interest to me, I save it into one big directory, and then Polarized goes in and ingests all of the papers and makes them available for me to read and annotate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What Roger did here was basically take his background in ML and built a set of tools to manage his learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I basically did the same thing when I first started working on Polar but I realized that this tool needs to be democratized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re going to be building in more cloud learning and big data capabilities in Polar in the next few months including
support for full-text search, clustering, auto-tagging, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The entire point of Polar is that we’re trying to democratize this technology and make it usable to the average person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an aside, it’s been really interesting to see who’s been using Polar.  Lots of PhD students, VCs, researchers, 
academics, scientists, etc.  Very exciting to see such amazingly smart people using the product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Polar Outage- Sept 18 2019</title><link href="https://getpolarized.io/2019/09/18/Polar-Outage-Sept-2019.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Polar Outage- Sept 18 2019" /><published>2019-09-18T09:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-09-18T09:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://getpolarized.io/2019/09/18/Polar-Outage-Sept-2019</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://getpolarized.io/2019/09/18/Polar-Outage-Sept-2019.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;polar-outage--sept-18-2019&quot;&gt;Polar Outage- Sept 18 2019&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had an outage last night for Polar cloud sync and our web application which was related to an issue in Google cloud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Users would have been unable to use the web application and cloud sync wouldn’t work properly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At 2 AM PST Google downgraded all of our accounts due to “activity”:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We received an email with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Billing was disabled for your project, or The billing account attached to your project was closed”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of our accounts were downgraded to the Spark plan (their lowest plan).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we figured out what was happening we reverted our billing to blaze (the proper plan) and about ten minutes 
later everything was functioning properly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This also coincided with a release which was just a coincidence.  Some of our users were saying that Polar was failing
after upgrading but it was just a timing issue.  Upon restart Polar does a full re-sync.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We apologize or the inconvenience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re still trying to investigate &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; this happened as there were no changes on our end and Google shouldn’t have
taken our projects offline.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Polar Outage- Sept 18 2019</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://getpolarized.io/assets/logo/icon.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Minimizing Defection Might be the Solution to the Tragedy of the Commons</title><link href="https://getpolarized.io/2019/07/26/Minimizing-Defection-Might-be-the-Solution-to-the-Tragedy-of-the-Commons.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Minimizing Defection Might be the Solution to the Tragedy of the Commons" /><published>2019-07-26T10:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-07-26T10:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://getpolarized.io/2019/07/26/Minimizing-Defection-Might-be-the-Solution-to-the-Tragedy-of-the-Commons</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://getpolarized.io/2019/07/26/Minimizing-Defection-Might-be-the-Solution-to-the-Tragedy-of-the-Commons.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;minimizing-defection-might-be-the-solution-to-the-tragedy-of-the-commons&quot;&gt;Minimizing Defection Might be the Solution to the Tragedy of the Commons.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being that my background is in CompSci I tend to think about thinks in terms of probabilities, statistics, game theory, 
and distributed systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve recently made what I think may be a unique observation about a number of social problems that might all be
related to one root cause - defection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I might be wrong but would love some feedback.  It’s an exceedingly complicated topic which has been researched for 
hundreds of years so it might be that this observation has been made before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My initial epiphany came while thinking about two main issues:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Corporations abusing their employees and the need to unionize.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Corporations all rushing towards some non-optimal solution in the pursuit of profit&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Consumers unwilling to purchase products even if purchasing them would fund a product they cared about.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s my assertion that these are all related to the tragedy of the commons. I’ll just quote from Wikipedia to save you a step:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The tragedy of the commons is a situation in a shared-resource system where individual users, acting independently
 according to their own self-interest, behave contrary to the common good of all users, by depleting or spoiling that
 resource through their collective action. The theory originated in an essay written in 1833 by the British economist
 William Forster Lloyd, who used a hypothetical example of the effects of unregulated grazing on common land (also known
 as a “common”) in Great Britain and Ireland.[1] The concept became widely known as the “tragedy of the commons” over a
 century later due to an article written by the American ecologist and philosopher Garrett Hardin in 1968.[2] In this
 modern economic context, commons is taken to mean any shared and unregulated resource such as atmosphere, oceans,
 rivers, fish stocks, roads and highways, or even an office refrigerator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d assert that the tragedy of the commons is actually a more general form of the prisoners dilemma (again, from &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Prisoner%27s_dilemma&quot;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The prisoner’s dilemma is a standard example of a game analyzed in game theory that shows why two completely rational
individuals might not cooperate, even if it appears that it is in their best interests to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of a prison term there’s the destruction of some resource and the tragedy of the commons is generalized to more actors.  Usually hundreds to thousands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;cheating-and-cynicism&quot;&gt;Cheating and Cynicism&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think the core issue in the above is defection - the idea that one player can decide to cheat the others for their own
benefit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The FEWER the actors the less probability that there will be defection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a completely hypothetical chart at what I think the rate of defection would look like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/GYGoVF4.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This would need to be validated experimentally but I suspect that the probability of cooperation (the opposite of
defection) would be inversely proportional to the size of the group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This would explain fundamental problems with collective action and why systems like communism are doomed to failure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you know the other person well and trust them, you’re probably not going to defect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, if you have thousands of people you’re going to be far far less trusting that someone isn’t going to defect and 
screw you over.  Hence &lt;em&gt;you’re&lt;/em&gt; more likely to defect as well!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a core observation.  The more actors in a class that CAN defect the higher the probability that they WILL defect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This why unions are so hard to form and manage.  There are thousands of people in a company and they all have conflicting
interests.  If they would hold their ground they could achieve their goals but they don’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why is that?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason they don’t is game theoretic and hence deterministic.  We won’t ever solve this problem until we reduce
the probability of defection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interestingly enough, the same situation applies to corporations creating externalities (destroying the environment, 
hurting their employees, etc).  They’re essentially forced into this behavior due to defection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your company cares about the environment but all your customers care about is price then the companies that have 
a higher priced product will go out of business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oddly enough these customers are also driven by defection.  Why care about the environment when no one else does?  Why
are you the only one who cares?  Why pay $15 a pound for steak when you can just pay $5?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interestingly enough, the optimum solution is always present when N=1.  If there’s just one actor (you) then you’re not
likely to destroy your own property.  The more actors present the higher chance that someone’s going to abuse the system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;a-protocol-for-minimizing-defection&quot;&gt;A Protocol for Minimizing Defection?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What if we could solve this problem through core changes in our society?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can’t help thinking that maybe some sort of smart contract could be used here or a system of opt-in benefits and harsh 
punishments for defection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m still working through what this would mean but I’ll illustrate some (flawed) ideas below to illustrate some potential 
solutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What if unions gave perks to employees including job references, health benefits, etc BUT to participate in the union 
you had to put forth a $5k bond.  This could be deducted slowly over time from your paycheck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you defect, the bond is revoked and you lose that money - permanently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll agree that this is a week solution as I mentioned I’m still trying to work on an ideal way to handle this problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consumers could do something similar for corporations as well.  Have reserved payments given out over time but only 
if the companies don’t create any externalities for which the consumer doesn’t approve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If these actors function collectively and make decisions as a group these could all be done automatically via simple
majority.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think regardless, identify the CORE issue here would allow us to keep working towards a goal.  The first step 
towards a solution is realizing the problem.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Minimizing Defection Might be the Solution to the Tragedy of the Commons.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://getpolarized.io/assets/logo/icon.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Polar 1.19.8 Released - Better Payments and Fixes</title><link href="https://getpolarized.io/2019/06/02/Polar-1-19-8.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Polar 1.19.8 Released - Better Payments and Fixes" /><published>2019-06-02T10:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-06-02T10:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://getpolarized.io/2019/06/02/Polar-1-19-8</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://getpolarized.io/2019/06/02/Polar-1-19-8.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;polar-1198-released---better-payments-and-fixes&quot;&gt;Polar 1.19.8 Released - Better Payments and Fixes&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
    We've revamped our payments system for Polar Premium and
    the biggest change is that we're now accepting payments
    via Stripe.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
    We've manually migrated accounts from Open Collective and
    your payments will still process there while you have a
    regular premium account.  If you have any issues please
    feel free to contact &lt;b&gt;support@getpolarized.io&lt;/b&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
    We're going to be working to bring on a few more premium
    features in the next couple weeks.  These include:


&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Watch directories that can automatically import documents into Polar.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Markdown support&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Dark mode&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
    We're not 100% certain of the timeline on these features
    as some of them are a bit difficult to implement.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
    We're also working on a few major changes that are taking
    a bit longer - mostly because they're very technically
    complicated.  These aren't available yet but are 50-80%
    complete.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
    This includes:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Folder view that extends our tagging system with a full hierarchy.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Tabbed browsing for the desktop / Electron version of Polar&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;ePub support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
    If you'd like to see these features sooner rather than
    later the best way you can help (besides a pull request)
    is to upgrade to &lt;a href=&quot;https://getpolarized.io/pricing.html&quot;&gt;
    Polar Premium&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Changes in 1.19.8 Include:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;New payment system for Polar premium based on Stripe.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Fixed bug when dragging area highlights.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Fixed regression in the webapp where PHZ files couldn't be loaded.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Polar 1.19.8 Released - Better Payments and Fixes</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://getpolarized.io/assets/logo/icon.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">GPT-2, the Destruction of the Web and Artificially Intelligent Textbooks</title><link href="https://getpolarized.io/2019/05/30/GPT2-Destruction-of-the-Web-and-Artificially-Intelligent-Textbooks.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="GPT-2, the Destruction of the Web and Artificially Intelligent Textbooks" /><published>2019-05-30T10:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-05-30T10:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://getpolarized.io/2019/05/30/GPT2-Destruction-of-the-Web-and-Artificially-Intelligent-Textbooks</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://getpolarized.io/2019/05/30/GPT2-Destruction-of-the-Web-and-Artificially-Intelligent-Textbooks.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/V8RyHZ9.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;gpt-2-the-destruction-of-the-web-and-artificially-intelligent-textbooks&quot;&gt;GPT-2, the Destruction of the Web and Artificially Intelligent Textbooks&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://openai.com/blog/better-language-models/&quot;&gt;GPT-2&lt;/a&gt; is a deep-learning
language model released by OpenAI a few months ago which is causing a bit of
controversy in the deep learning community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Due to our concerns about malicious applications of the technology, we are not
releasing the trained model. As an experiment in responsible disclosure, we are
instead releasing a much smaller model for researchers to experiment with, as
well as a technical paper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OpenAI actually took a conservative position and decided to hold off from
releasing the model due to the potential impact on society.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is one of the first emerging technologies that &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; frightens me.
There’s a massive potential or abuse here and I don’t think society is ready for
it just yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With many disruptive technologies we generally have a few years to come to grips
with the problems they might cause. Robotics, Crispr, and other technologies are
still a few years away from really impacting our lives (however it plays out).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not true with GPT-2 - it’s here today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;background&quot;&gt;Background&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GPT-2 is a deep learning model released by OpenAI back in February which they
built by indexing 40GB of web content derived from a web crawl.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They indexed about 8M pages and then dumped it into a neural network&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It builds an internal linguistic model of the underlying text represented as a
neural network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This helps it understand the actual text but also it’s generative. This means
it can build NEW text based on a prompt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a short example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;system-prompt&quot;&gt;System Prompt&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This part was generated by a human as the input prompt:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In a shocking finding, scientist discovered a herd of unicorns living in a
remote, previously unexplored valley, in the Andes Mountains. Even more
surprising to the researchers was the fact that the unicorns spoke perfect
English.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;model-completion&quot;&gt;Model Completion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was generated by GPT-2, a computer:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The scientist named the population, after their distinctive horn, Ovid’s
Unicorn. These four-horned, silver-white unicorns were previously unknown to
science.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Now, after almost two centuries, the mystery of what sparked this odd
phenomenon is finally solved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Dr. Jorge Pérez, an evolutionary biologist from the University of La Paz, and
several companions, were exploring the Andes Mountains when they found a small
valley, with no other animals or humans. Pérez noticed that the valley had what
appeared to be a natural fountain, surrounded by two peaks of rock and silver
snow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;… this is just a short excerpt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can &lt;a href=&quot;https://openai.com/blog/better-language-models/&quot;&gt;read more here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;could-it-destroy-the-web&quot;&gt;Could it Destroy the Web?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The web is built on a number of assumptions which aren’t necessarily true
any longer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, that only humans can write legitimate content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the past machine-generated text seemed, well, robotic. If you used a markov
chain to generate text it sounded like you would expect - like canned text.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It went off topic. Didn’t make sense. They were words. They were a subset of 
language but they didn’t have much meaning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can get a sense of how this works by using auto-complete on your mobile phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you start off with a sample sentence and let it auto-complete and just select 
the first match it will sound rather - insane.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s an example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On my phone I entered “The cat is outside” and then hit next again and again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My came up with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The cat is outside and is never told about Jesus do they go to the emergency
place of his own and they are crawling to be my friend.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I mean, those are words. That’s technically a sentence. But it doesn’t make a 
ton of sense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GPT-2 can write entire articles of text that sound like they were written by a
human.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only do they seem human they’re also readable - you won’t get bored either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is going to lead to a &lt;em&gt;massive&lt;/em&gt; amount of Google spam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you can write content for cheap you can use arbitrage and post content on the
web and then run ads against it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you can generate gigabytes of content for pennies you can make a lot of money
just cranking out fake content and spamming search engines..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Legitimate marketers are going do to this too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why write new content when you could just crawl your competitors site and have
it generate content based on &lt;em&gt;their&lt;/em&gt; data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or just crawl your own content and have it generate new articles based on your
current articles as a system prompt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What else could we do?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You could create fake news.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fake scientific research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You could spam your competitors support queue with fake technical support requests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The list goes on and on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any background in SEO or search your heart is probably racing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take a 20 minute break and meditate. We’ll be here when you get back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;whats-the-upside&quot;&gt;What’s the upside?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is there any upside?  There is. I think it could have a dramatic and amazing
impact on spaced repetition and cognitive science.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GPT-2 could help build question and answer pairs by bulk processing large
textbooks to build flashcards for spaced repetition systems like Anki and
&lt;a href=&quot;https://getpolarized.io/&quot;&gt;Polar&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It could also help with the raw &lt;em&gt;understanding&lt;/em&gt; of the text so you could ask it
questions and it could provide you with answers. Far better than simple
full-text search!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Full-text search will get you closer to an answer but you still have to spend a
bit of time reading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With GPT-2 it could just flat out give you the answer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve ever read Diamond Age it could help build a “Young Lady’s Illustrated
Primer” or an artificially intelligent textbook that you can interact with
directly!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You would literally be able to interact with a textbook and ask it questions
from the material you’re reading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Textbooks would no longer be sterile and inert. It could suggest other reading
based on your interests. You could interact with it and it could actually
&lt;em&gt;teach&lt;/em&gt; you directly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It can’t &lt;em&gt;understand&lt;/em&gt; the text in the classical sense than you or I can. You 
can’t ask it mathematical questions and expect answers or questions that 
are more philosophical in nature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those still require humans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;mitigation&quot;&gt;Mitigation&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is some risk mitigation we could pursue. We could require public keys 
for users and only index content that is signed and build a trust model
similar to Pagerank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Humans can only write so much content. By using this model you’re going to 
throttle people by forcing their rank to flow between the graph of the web 
of trust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People can create fake keys of course. They can fake key after key for their
fake robots but they have to attract REAL humans to certify them at some point
and you would only flow so much rank from a real human forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If search engines employed auditors to find and validate real people we could
keep the web from becoming owned by AI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not perfect but I think there’s a path forward here though going in depth
is a bit ouf of scope for this article.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-could-stop-gpt-2&quot;&gt;What Could Stop GPT-2?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s say we collectively decide that building and releasing something like 
GPT-2 is a bad idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How could we stop it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can’t. It’s just a matter of time until this technology is democratized and
in the hands of everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The prices of GPUs and cloud computing is just getting cheaper and cheaper and 
eventually this is going to become commoditized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In five or so years you’ll be able to build a model like GPT-2 in a few days to 
weeks with very little funding and with off the shelf tools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re going to have to deal with this one way or another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GPT-2 is really frightening but if we can mitigate the risks we might be able
to use these systems in the future and focus mostly on the positives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re going to need to educate older voters and people naive about modern
technology on the risks of trusting fake news and deep fakes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This might be an uphill battle though. We already have fake news and we haven’t
done a good job dealing with it already. How are we going to deal with it when
its gets far far worse?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">13 Lucky Tips for using Anki and Spaced Repetition in 2019</title><link href="https://getpolarized.io/2019/05/25/13-lucky-tips-for-using-anki-and-spaced-repetition-2019.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="13 Lucky Tips for using Anki and Spaced Repetition in 2019" /><published>2019-05-25T10:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-05-25T10:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://getpolarized.io/2019/05/25/13-lucky-tips-for-using-anki-and-spaced-repetition-2019</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://getpolarized.io/2019/05/25/13-lucky-tips-for-using-anki-and-spaced-repetition-2019.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/FeMzRL1.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;13-lucky-tips-for-using-anki-and-spaced-repetition-in-2019&quot;&gt;13 Lucky Tips for using Anki and Spaced Repetition in 2019&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the past few years I’ve been using Anki to capture anything I want to
remember long term.  If I’m reading an important Wikipedia page I save it to
&lt;a href=&quot;https://getpolarized.io/&quot;&gt;Polar&lt;/a&gt;, annotate it directly, then create flashcards 
from the annotations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do this to my textbooks and anything else I find important enough to remember
forever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason SR is so effective for me is it allows me to efficiently schedule
when to review the material. I’m not constantly reviewing material I already
know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are my tips and tricks for using Anki and SR for language learning, pursing
a medical degree, undergraduate degree, or just trying to be the smartest person
in the room!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These tips will work on any spaced repetition platform including Anki, Quizlet,
or Memrise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;understand-how-it-works&quot;&gt;Understand How It Works&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, you should read a bit about &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spaced_repetition&quot;&gt;spaced repetition&lt;/a&gt; and make sure you know how
it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is key or you’re going to make silly mistakes and revert to the old strategy
of learning and cramming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid border border-secondary&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/otv7GF0.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;make-it-easy&quot;&gt;Make it Easy.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Creating flashcards needs to be easy use a tool like
&lt;a href=&quot;https://getpolarized.io/&quot;&gt;Polar&lt;/a&gt; so that you can create flashcards, comments,
and annotations directly while you’re reading the material.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once created the flashcards can all be sync’d to Anki in batch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This prevents you from going back and forth between Anki and your reading app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, Polar supports incremental reading so you can go back and forth
between books and continue where you left off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid border border-secondary&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/rbAwfR6.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;active-recall&quot;&gt;Active Recall&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should also understand why &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Active_recall&quot;&gt;active recall&lt;/a&gt; is so important&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Active recall is a principle of efficient learning, which claims the need to
actively stimulate memory during the learning process. It contrasts with passive
review, in which the learning material is processed passively (e.g. by reading,
watching, etc.). For example, reading a text about George Washington, with no
further action, is a passive review. Answering the question “Who was the first
US President?”, is active recall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Essentially you want everything to be a question and you want to have to think of the
answer. It’s this thinking process which allows your brain to map weights to specific
neurons and actually learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t give leading questions or give your self hints to the answer. If you don’t
know the questions that’s fine.  Just fail it so it’s brought up again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;habit-habit-habit&quot;&gt;Habit, Habit, Habit.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You couldn’t sit down at the end of the month and brush your teeth for 2-3 hours
to make up for not brushing would you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This has to be a habit. You have to do it every day for 15-45 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do it when you have dead time.  During  your commute. While you’re in line at the DMV.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While you’re bored.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;85-90-difficulty&quot;&gt;85-90 Difficulty&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should try to target 85-90% difficulty for your cards. If you go into Anki 
stats you can see the difficulty level for your recent usage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Too easy and you’re probably reviewing too often (and wasting time).  Too hard
and you’re not going to learn anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You want it to be difficult to not too difficulty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately Anki doesn’t tun itself so you have to tune Anki directly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This can be adjusted in the per-deck settings by changing the ease factors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;think-long-term&quot;&gt;Think LONG Term.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t give up on cards after you’ve finished a class or other milestone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cool thing about SR is that you can keep the material forever.  If you paid
money to learn Calculus you might as well keep it.  Once you’ve learned it
using SR is mostly about maintenance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since you know the material the scheduling will get farther and farther in the
future and there won’t be such a massive burden.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;use-the-right-card-type&quot;&gt;Use the Right Card Type&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should prefer to use question and answer cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are in the form of&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Q: What is the capital of California?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A: Sacramento&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This would be as opposed to cloze deletion cards like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Sacramento] is the capital of California.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the above the ‘Sacramento’ string is hidden.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cloze deletion cards might seem easy but they often give away context clues
which weakens the entire point of SR.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;cloze-deletions-for-languages&quot;&gt;Cloze Deletions for Languages.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s one main exception for cloze deletion cards - languages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cloze can be good to help with grammar and sentence structure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They should NOT replace Q/A cards though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a given word you should have the definition and the forward and reverse translation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;person-cards--remember-a-persons-face&quot;&gt;Person cards.  Remember a Person’s Face!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is one of my favorite hacks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have trouble with matching names to faces and I used to avoid talking to people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I just create a card with their picture and the answer is their name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s really help avoid awkward social situations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid border border-secondary&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/qP4My84.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;related-cards&quot;&gt;Related Cards&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re struggling with a card try creating related cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example if you have difficulties remembering the reasons for the start of WWII
make flashcards about those reasons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to include Pearl Harbor for example maybe you include facts about
the ships or the types of attacks that were involved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;create-only-beneficial-cards&quot;&gt;Create only Beneficial Cards.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t create nonsense cards. Ask yourself will this really help you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember that SR is an efficient scheduler so going from 5-10k cards isn’t 2x
more work.  It is initially but quickly your spacings increase and you’re going
to just be reviewing a few cards per day again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, by only keeping important cards in there this helps you avoid card
burnout since you’re never wondering “why” you’re learning these cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The why is because they’re valuable!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Knowing key facts might still land you that job.  If you know a technical term
during an interview or due diligence it could help convince the interviewer that
you know your stuff.  Consider adding it anyway!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;use-shingling-to-remember-speeches&quot;&gt;Use ‘shingling’ to Remember Speeches&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do not include entire speeches to remember. Instead. Use overlapped sentences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example. If you want to remember the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Four score and seven years ago our fathers brought forth on this continent a new nation, conceived in Liberty, and dedicated to the proposition that all men are created equal.
Now we are engaged in a great civil war, testing whether that nation or any nation so conceived and so dedicated, can long endure.
We are met on a great battle-field of that war.
We have come to dedicate a portion of that field, as a final resting place for those who here gave their lives that that nation might live.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Break this out into three cards:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Q: Four score and seven years ago our fathers brought forth on this continent a new nation, conceived in Liberty, and dedicated to the proposition that all men are created equal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A: Now we are engaged in a great civil war, testing whether that nation or any nation so conceived and so dedicated, can long endure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;–&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Q: Now we are engaged in a great civil war, testing whether that nation or any nation so conceived and so dedicated, can long endure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A: We are met on a great battle-field of that war.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;–&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Q: We are met on a great battle-field of that war.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A: We have come to dedicate a portion of that field, as a final resting place for those who here gave their lives that that nation might live.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will help you connect the parts without having to choke on a massive card with the entire speech.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;use-absurdity-and-keep-it-fun&quot;&gt;Use Absurdity and Keep it Fun&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you were driving to work and you saw a naked man riding a horse on the side
of the road would you need to remember it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Would you have to write it down?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No. It would burn in your mind.  You’d remember this image for a decade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do this for your anki cards you’re trying to remember.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s say you met a guy and his name is “Mark Nun”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(I just made this up btw. If your name is Mark Nun we don’t know each other!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Picture this guy as an actual nun wearing a nun’s uniform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’re never going to forget this guy’s name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do this all the time and it’s a great hack.  You can do this for your cards to by
mapping images with the cards that are absurd.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;use-extra-fields&quot;&gt;Use Extra Fields&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Create an ‘extra’ field with your cards so that you can add notes and pictures
so that when you fail to remember you can get back to the original context.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll often put the book information.  The actual text of where I saw the card, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m working on a feature for Polar to add this directly so that when you create
a flashcard in Polar we automatically create a card with the context so you 
can click back to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The initial version will probably just have a link back to the Polar webapp to
avoid bloating Anki with too many images.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;use-stories-and-etymology&quot;&gt;Use Stories and Etymology&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Attach ‘extra’ stories to the material as above but make them stories or use
imagery to remember the material.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve found that etymology works VERY well for learning languages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example.  The German word for sea is meer which is related to the English word
marine which is also related to mare (spanish / italian for sea).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those connections make it easier to remember.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SR won’t replace the work of actually understanding the material.  This is still
your job.  If you’re still confused on a subject try reading it from different
perspectives of from different authors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use the above tips to keep moving forward with spaced repetition. Use a tool
like Polar to easily create flashcards and sync them to Anki.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sure you’re also using the right Anki plugins and that you’re using it to
full effect.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Portable Web Documents - An Alternative to PDF based on HTML5 and Web Standards</title><link href="https://getpolarized.io/2019/05/11/portable-web-documents.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Portable Web Documents - An Alternative to PDF based on HTML5 and Web Standards" /><published>2019-05-11T10:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-05-11T10:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://getpolarized.io/2019/05/11/portable-web-documents</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://getpolarized.io/2019/05/11/portable-web-documents.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid&quot; src=&quot;https://getpolarized.io/assets/images/portable-web-documents-scaled.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;portable-web-documents---an-alternative-to-pdf-based-on-html5-and-web-standards&quot;&gt;Portable Web Documents - An Alternative to PDF based on HTML5 and Web Standards&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Portable Web Documents are a technology similar to PDFs (Portable Document
Format) implemented in Polar which support offline caching of full HTML
documents, and with (in the future) improved support for video, charts, and
other compelling features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Polar uses PWDs and PDFs to manage the users reading and allows the user to keep
all documents in a central repository and allows for suspend/resume of reading,
tagging, and annotation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-responsive embed-responsive-16by9&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe class=&quot;embed-responsive-item&quot; width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZkEo5YmNukY&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-a-new-document-format&quot;&gt;Why a New Document Format?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PDFs are great and have gotten us pretty far to date but I think their future 
is limited.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They’re perfect for laying out text and charts in a static format plus
preserving the document long term and of course sending them via email or
storing them in the cloud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But they also have a few major limitations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They only support static layouts - not fluid/dynamic layouts that change when
you resize the page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t have support for features like video, animated images, interactive charts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They also have limited form support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Printing HTML pages as PDFs is also difficult as HTML wasn’t designed to be 
paginated and without explicit support for CSS form-feed on certain items 
(large images) the resulting PDF becomes mangled and hard to read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;html-in-a-portable-document-format&quot;&gt;HTML in a Portable Document Format?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What if we could combine the benefits of PDFs with the benefits of HTML content?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HTML is amazing and supports a lot of compelling features that are not possible 
in PDF but they’re also limited in a few key areas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If any of the resources in your document vanishes it’s effectively broken.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It would also be nice to have the ability to cache a page offline in perpetuity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HTML pages can (for the most part) be censored.  If your ISP or government orders
a website offline you might be out of luck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;portable-web-documents-to-the-rescue&quot;&gt;Portable Web Documents to the Rescue&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Polar supports a file format called Portable Web Documents (PWDs) (note
internally we still refer to these as PHZs since we’re still in development of a 
finalize document format) which supports the best of both worlds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PWDs are essentially a full HTML document including all dependent resources 
bundled in a zip file archive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are some associated file formats like WARC and MHTML that attempt to solve
this problem but only really get you about 30-50% of a complete solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;WARCs or example can’t actually be loaded properly in Chrome due to chrome’s 
inability to handle service workers elegantly in chrome extensions or to serve
resources directly via request handlers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Request handlers can only redirect you to a new URL.  They can’t really replace 
content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to cross origin issues and other web complexities it’s better to take the 
entire document, rewrite the URLs and properly handle dependent resources,
and re-bundle into a new layout which bypasses all these technical challenges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;capture-and-storage&quot;&gt;Capture and Storage.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Capture is by far the biggest challenge in making PWDs as representing the
original form an intent of the web designer (and the reader) as a document can
sometimes be very challenging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To create a PWD we first have to capture it and this requires support from the 
browser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now Polar implements capture via Electron.  We allow the user to preview 
the URL then store the data directly into a rewritten PWD image.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the web isn’t really static anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can’t just take the CSS stylesheets and &lt;img /&gt; references and store them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You also have to look at the &lt;em&gt;live&lt;/em&gt; DOM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many toolkits like React actually modify the DOM directly and manipulate and 
redefine CSS styles.  These have to be written correctly or you will break
page load.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you have to deactivate all scripts and event handlers so that when the 
PWD loads it’s in a neutralized document. You wouldn’t want scripts running due
to potential security issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you have to think about web fonts, iframes, and potentially extract metadata 
from the page including title, description and possibly microdata so that the 
PWD has the same metadata exposed in its internal metadata manifest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is just an abbreviated list of course of some of the challenges.  There are
another 10-20 issues that we have to be careful when creating PWDs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We still have some challenges now that we’re unsure how to handle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, some iframes only load when they’re visible so we enabled a cheat 
to expand the preview window to trigger them to load.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, this caused another ugly bug where some websites like to ‘auto-paginate’
so that when you’re at the bottom of a page you’re given a full related article
in the hope that you stay with the site longer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These issues are mutually exclusive though.  A solution for one breaks the
solution for the other so we’re stuck in a catch 22 until we have a workaround.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;current-limitations&quot;&gt;Current Limitations&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We do have some limitations currently which I’d like to lift in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Technically we only support static layouts. PWDs could also support fully fluid
layouts as well which would be really exciting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It would be nice to support caching of video, audio, images, and interactive 
charts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This would make PWDs sort of like a ‘young lady’s illustrated primer’ (if you’ve 
ever read Diamond Age) where a book is now fully interactive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This would also mean that this interactivity would work offline and be fully 
interactive!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now Polar is limited to capturing within Electron which means we can’t 
access the user’s cookies and prevents some URLs from loading properly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re porting our capture code to our chrome extension to mitigate this and 
this should be fixed shortly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-future&quot;&gt;The Future&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Polar wanted something like PWDs so that we can enable some cool features in the
future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first (which we have now actually) is just full offline archival of web
pages to prevent them from being deleted.  If the content is important you don’t
want it to vanish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also want a way for users to collaborate around web content.  Add
annotations, comments, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We ideally don’t want the content to vanish so PWDs allow us to keep it
associated with the users document store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’d also like to enable features where users can exchange documents directly 
without relying on the original site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This allows us to bypass censorship for documents that might be sensitive 
outside of their host country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also want to support video, audio, and interactive charting formats. Video
is a bit difficult as we need to determine how to stream and store the video 
within the compressed archive and stream it efficiently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our plan is to use web workers and service workers to decompress it in a 
background thread.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interactive charts and spreadsheets are also compelling but I don’t want to just
enable raw Javascript support.  It might be possible that something like WASM
could solve this by putting the controls in a sandbox.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also need a strategy to preserve teh fonts long term.  Right now we don’t
store the fonts along with the PWD because they can increase the size by about
2x.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It might be nice for a system like Polar to have sort of a shared CDN so that
fonts are only stored once but this creates problems with dependencies which 
aren’t ideal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;working-with-portable-web-documents&quot;&gt;Working with Portable Web Documents&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to play with the current version of PWDs download Polar and take
it for a spin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now you can view them in the webapp but can’t create them so you need to
download the desktop version of Polar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re planning on fixing this issue in the next big refactor to embed the
capture process in our chrome extension.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once created the captured document is stored within Polar as a normal document 
just like any PDF doc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You get all the normal Polar features including tagging, annotation, flashcard
creation, cloud sync, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any feedback please jump on our Discord or create a github issue.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Polar 1.19 Released With Area Highlights and Updated Annotations View</title><link href="https://getpolarized.io/2019/05/10/polar-1-19-0-with-area-highlights.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Polar 1.19 Released With Area Highlights and Updated Annotations View" /><published>2019-05-10T10:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-05-10T10:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://getpolarized.io/2019/05/10/polar-1-19-0-with-area-highlights</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://getpolarized.io/2019/05/10/polar-1-19-0-with-area-highlights.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;polar-119-released-with-area-highlights-and-updated-annotations-view&quot;&gt;Polar 1.19 Released With Area Highlights and Updated Annotations View&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-responsive embed-responsive-16by9&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe class=&quot;embed-responsive-item&quot; width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/TDYDOGGTPls&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Polar 1.19 has been a lot of work but it’s finally out the door.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you haven’t updated Polar in a while make sure you’re on the latest version 
by going to Help | About or Help | Check for Updates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a few we want to highlight about this release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;area-highlights&quot;&gt;Area Highlights&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Area highlights are now shown in the sidebar and updated and resized while you
drag the area highlight box.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was frequently requested by our users and allows you to select mathematical
figures and illustrations for annotation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid img-shadow&quot; src=&quot;/assets/screenshots/1-19-sidebar.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;updated-annotations-view&quot;&gt;Updated Annotations View&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve updated the annotations view to show preview annotations and a better view
of each annotation including showing area highlights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid img-shadow&quot; src=&quot;https://getpolarized.io/assets/screenshots/annotations-view.webp&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;color-selector&quot;&gt;Color Selector&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s now an advanced color selector for highlights and this expands us to 12
different colors.  We’re going to expand the palette in the future but this is
already a step in the right directly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Technically we support any RGB value but we’re limiting the colors you can
select for now just to make the UI simpler and easy to use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid img-shadow&quot; src=&quot;/assets/screenshots/1-19-colors.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;performance-improvements&quot;&gt;Performance Improvements&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve also implemented some more major performance improvements when working
with larger documents and larger sets of annotations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;native-pdf-handling-in-web-extension-disabled&quot;&gt;Native PDF Handling in Web Extension Disabled&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve had to remove the native PDF handling in our web extension.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This feature automatically previewed and added a PDF to the Polar webapp while
browsing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had to disable it due to cross domain security issues we weren’t able to fix.
This might be enabled again in a future version of Polar.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Polar 1.19 Released With Area Highlights and Updated Annotations View</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Polar 1.18.0 Released</title><link href="https://getpolarized.io/2019/04/25/polar-1-18-0.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Polar 1.18.0 Released" /><published>2019-04-25T10:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-04-25T10:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://getpolarized.io/2019/04/25/polar-1-18-0</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://getpolarized.io/2019/04/25/polar-1-18-0.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;polar-1180-released&quot;&gt;Polar 1.18.0 Released&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This release mostly focused on improving stability
and implementing a few key UI features.  This
upgrades us to Electron 5.x which as needed for
some users who were experiencing severe latency
using Polar on Linux.  We also resolve a key issue
with non-atomic writes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This includes a good chunk of the new sharing
functionality but it’s not enabled yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Big upgrade to latest version of Electron. Electron v5.0.0, Chromium v73.0.3683.119, Node v12.0.0, v8 v7.3.492.27-electron.0. This should hopefully fix a major latency issue some users were seeing on Ubuntu/Linux.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Major performance fix on large PDFs.  Scrolling should be dramatically improved.  There's still a small latency issue we're seeing but already performance is dramatically improved.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Enabled atomic writes again for all platforms.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Filtering for tags now lists the tags alphabetically

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Right click on text highlight now add 'scroll into view'

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Upgraded to latest version of Typescript 3.4.3

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fixed regression where progress wasn't being updated when progress messages were being sent from the renderer process.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fixed bug which resorted in two file uploads to firebase while cloud sync was operational. For large files this was very painful and resorted in 2x data being uploaded.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fixed bug where the UI would break when both filtering and removing tags on a document that was visible.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Increased the sidebar a bit to accommodate updating comments without overflow of the summernote bar.

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using the same account widget on web + desktop now.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Polar 1.18.0 Released</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://getpolarized.io/assets/logo/icon.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Polar Mission Statement and Design for a Personal Knowledge Repository</title><link href="https://getpolarized.io/2019/04/11/Polar-Mission-Statement.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Polar Mission Statement and Design for a Personal Knowledge Repository" /><published>2019-04-11T06:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-04-11T06:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://getpolarized.io/2019/04/11/Polar-Mission-Statement</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://getpolarized.io/2019/04/11/Polar-Mission-Statement.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid&quot; src=&quot;https://getpolarized.io/assets/images/darts-scaled.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This document is under construction and still evolving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;polar-mission-statement-and-design-for-a-personal-knowledge-repository&quot;&gt;Polar Mission Statement and Design for a Personal Knowledge Repository&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Polar has a broad mission statement to provide high quality tools for document
annotation, management of documents (tagging, storage, etc) and sharing of 
content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a great deal of overlap in the technical requirements needed for these
features so Polar provides a great deal of functionality to provide a
comprehensive personal knowledge repository and distributed content management
platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;roadmap&quot;&gt;Roadmap&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See the roadmap for &lt;a href=&quot;https://getpolarized.io/2019/04/10/Roadmap-Q2-Q3-2019.html&quot;&gt;Q2/Q3/Q4 2019&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The roadmap living document so please check back over time to see how it evolves
especially as new features are released.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;use-cases&quot;&gt;Use Cases&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Polar focuses on a number of key use cases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The core is document management which provides about 70% of the technical
complexity and allows us to re-use this infrastructure for the other use cases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each additional use case builds upon but shares the core functionality to avoid
technical complications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;document-management&quot;&gt;Document Management&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Document management is used by nearly all additional layers within Polar.  This
includes basic functionality like adding documents, supporting multiple formats,
storing metadata (title, author, etc) and handles replication, document
integrity, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Functionally, this includes features like tagging, flagging, archiving, updating
metadata, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;incremental-reading&quot;&gt;Incremental Reading&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Allows the user to keep track of their position using pagemarks, update their
pagemarks as they read documents, find new documents to read, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also keep track of core stats including number or documents read per day, etc
to encourage the user to hit their reading goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;annotation&quot;&gt;Annotation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Supports text and area highlighting, comments, flashcards, etc. The user can
attach annotations directly to documents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Annotations are top level metadata and can be exported, copied, and shared 
between users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;document-sharing-and-collaboration&quot;&gt;Document Sharing and Collaboration&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Document sharing allows others to view and share documents you’re reading, and annotating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a key Polar function as we want to test collaborative sharing to improve
knowledge retention using flashcards, and annotations to allow users who are 
sharing the same documents to actively collaborate towards a better experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, users could collaboratively build flashcards, add video, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We could also use this to automatically suggest flashcards for users of 
documents that are being shared with Polar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This way you could add a text-book and have pre-built flashcards already 
compiled and easily added with one click.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;bibliography-management&quot;&gt;Bibliography Management&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is primarily used for the scientific community and involves lookup of
document metadata via DOI, preserving extended metadata including author
information, and supports exporting selected documents as a bibliography.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;web-archival&quot;&gt;Web Archival&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Annotating web content is irrelevant if the document can be deleted by the site
thereby invalidating your annotations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Polar supports storing web content offline supporting annotations against
content that may or may not be deleted (or updated) by the original site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We plan on extending this use case to both improve archival in general but also 
support more transparent archives that seem like real web pages within your web 
browser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also intend on supporting annotations for content which isn’t necessarily
cached.  This functionality should allow Polar to be used by more users as it
should be much easier to annotate content when it’s just a native web page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;spaced-repetition-and-flashcard-management&quot;&gt;Spaced Repetition and Flashcard Management&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having all your reading at your fingertips is pointless if it’s quickly
forgotten.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Polar currently implements spaced repetition by supporting easy flashcard
creation and attaching these to text/area highlights directly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Flashcards can then be sync’d directly to Anki.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We tend to continue supporting Anki for power users for the forseeable future
but also want to support basic spaced repetition within Polar directly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will help people who aren’t Anki power users get started with SR without 
having to commit to Anki, add the plugin, create an account for sync there, 
install the app on their phone, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;5d-internet&quot;&gt;5D Internet&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Polar provides a five dimensional (5D) web platform.  We assert that the current
Internet is three-dimensional (3D) with traditional pages and links forming
nodes, edges and building a graph representation of the web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re adding the following dimensions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;fourth-dimension-time&quot;&gt;Fourth Dimension: Time&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Polar supports a content addressable storage scheme where documents are 
represented by their hash, not URL.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This allows us to store web pages in portable web archive formats (bundled as 
one document) which can be stored in perpetuity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This allows users to lookup content in their personal repository and have 
multiple copies of the document based on time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When connected this provides for an Internet-scale Internet Archive whereby 
users are individually archiving portions of the Internet. [^internet-scale-archiving]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;fifth-dimension-annotation&quot;&gt;Fifth Dimension: Annotation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Users can annotate documents in Polar including adding text and area highlights,
comments, and flashcards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This data is valuable to the individual but also to the web community at large.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TODO: Expand on this in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;federated-data&quot;&gt;Federated Data&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The underlying Polar data model is not specific to any type of network or 
storage infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;beyond-standards&quot;&gt;Beyond standards:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Web standards are only one part of what we’re trying to address.  Without 
millions of users using Polar as a integral part of our workflow we will not be
successful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To that end we have to have to focus on growth, UI/UX, support, mobile, and 
accessibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;corporate-and-non-profit-setup&quot;&gt;Corporate and Non-Profit Setup&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There will effectively be two organizations setup to support Polar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PolarOrg will support Polar as an Open Source project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PolarCom will sell cloud storage, private team sharing, and additional premium 
features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s our goal that the vast majority of users using Polar will use the platform 
for free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re trying to target roughly 95% of users on Polar will not pay and will be 
on a freemium model.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order for Polar to be competitive there must be an economic component to 
continue funding development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Otherwise, we risk our ideas and technology being stolen by other companies who
wouldn’t aggressively support the rights (and goals) of our user base.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;user-rights&quot;&gt;User Rights&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Polar wants to aggressively support the rights of our user base.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re not interested in doing anything evil.  Without your trust we believe 
this will hurt our mission.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This includes but is not limited to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;data-portability&quot;&gt;Data Portability&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should be able to easily access your data in easy to work with file formats
and export to 3rd party services at any time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;you-data-is-your-data&quot;&gt;You Data is Your Data&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Polar will never attempt to take exclusive ownership of your data and will only 
pursue reasonable rights to access your data for your use or the use of our data
partners (cloud service infrastructure) when you give us access.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Polar will require non-exclusive rights to have access to your data when using
cloud services including sync to mobile, web, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We may also engage in data partnerships which will be disclosed and will only 
do so for the benefits of our user base.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically, we’re not interested in doing anything evil and will only use your 
data for your benefit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;encryption&quot;&gt;Encryption&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will make reasonable attempts at making encrypting your data when reasonable
and at rest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re also investigating private encrypted end-to-end datastores for private 
and sensitive data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;desktop-only&quot;&gt;Desktop-only&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have every intention to continue to support desktop-only and offline-only 
usage where your data is not sync’d to the cloud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If cloud-only features are built (for example full-text search) we will not 
force uses to use cloud services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;federation&quot;&gt;Federation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Federation allows Polar to tie in different backend storage providers which 
could have different properties, security and privacy features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Polar supports federation through the concept of Datastores which provides a 
high level interface for reading and writing data, subscribing to events, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently Polar supports three datastores:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;disk&quot;&gt;Disk&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Provides a local storage for the desktop app and allows user to read and
write data without any major privacy considerations inherent with cloud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;firebase&quot;&gt;Firebase&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stores data in Google Firebase to provide cloud functionality including web
and mobile support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;cloud&quot;&gt;Cloud&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Provides a hybrid between Disk+Firebase for the desktop cloud sync across devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;future-datastores&quot;&gt;Future Datastores&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Polar provides for a Datastore interface which means we can easily implement
new technologies for data storage in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Filecoin is an example of an attractive Datastore which we might implement in 
the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;long-term-archival&quot;&gt;Long-Term Archival&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to the importance of Polar data we’re committed to verifying that documents
stored in Polar are preserved long-term.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This include selecting reliable file formats and using web standards as much as 
possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[^internet-scale-archiving] At some point we might allow users to share documents
but there are privacy concerns we have to address here as web documents served
to users might have PII data embedded within them and we also have to comply
with local laws as well as be respectful of user privacy.  Initially this ]
functionality won’t be enabled but it’s a sub-project we’d like to pursue in 
the future and might be possible for some fraction of the documents indexed 
when we can identify that they have zero PII.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry></feed>