<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://getpolarized.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://getpolarized.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-12-21T08:02:29-08:00</updated><id>https://getpolarized.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">POLAR - Easily manage your PDFs, web content, and notes.</title><subtitle>A powerful document manager for Mac, Windows, and Linux for managing web content, books, and notes and supports tagging, annotation, highlighting and keeps track of your reading progress.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Polar 1.80 - Manual Update Required for Desktop Users</title><link href="https://getpolarized.io/2019/12/20/1-80-Manual-Update-for-Desktop-Users.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Polar 1.80 - Manual Update Required for Desktop Users" /><published>2019-12-20T08:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2019-12-20T08:00:00-08:00</updated><id>https://getpolarized.io/2019/12/20/1-80-Manual-Update-for-Desktop-Users</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://getpolarized.io/2019/12/20/1-80-Manual-Update-for-Desktop-Users.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;polar-180---manual-update-required-for-desktop-users&quot;&gt;Polar 1.80 - Manual Update Required for Desktop Users&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Polar 1.80 for MacOS and Windows requires users to manually update to the latest version by &lt;a href=&quot;https://getpolarized.io/download.html&quot;&gt;manually downloading and
installing the latest version&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re very sorry for the inconvenience.  There was a bug in Electron &amp;gt;7.1.2 that broke updates for all Electron
applications.  I’ve filed bugs against the Electron project to hopefully fix this before it impacts other projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We aggressively test all major releases but didn’t think that a small point upgrade would have such a massive 
implication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving forward, we’re going to be migrating to a new build system which automatically tests the update system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This should prevent the problem from happening again.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Polar 1.80 - Manual Update Required for Desktop Users</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Polar 1.80 - Enhanced Mobile, Spaces within Tags and Special Holiday Offer</title><link href="https://getpolarized.io/2019/12/16/1-80-Enhanced-Mobile-Windows-Spaces-within-Tags.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Polar 1.80 - Enhanced Mobile, Spaces within Tags and Special Holiday Offer" /><published>2019-12-16T08:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2019-12-16T08:00:00-08:00</updated><id>https://getpolarized.io/2019/12/16/1-80-Enhanced-Mobile-Windows-Spaces-within-Tags</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://getpolarized.io/2019/12/16/1-80-Enhanced-Mobile-Windows-Spaces-within-Tags.html">&lt;p&gt;We have a new version of Polar out with some really interesting features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further, since holiday season is upon us, we are offering a special 1-year deal for Polar Premium for $19.95. That’s
a 50% discount on the regular price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;holiday-discount&quot;&gt;Holiday Discount&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;img-responsive mb-2&quot; style=&quot;max-height: 350px&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/QlytaB8.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve decided to offer a 1 year license of Polar for just $19.95.  Normally the bronze version of Polar is $4.99 
per month so this is nearly a $40 savings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to do this because a number of our student users commented that paying per month was expensive and $4.99 per
month was difficult when you’re living out of a dorm and eating ramen noodles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When 2.0 arrives, which should land sometime in January, the mobile flashcard review is going to be a premium feature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a great opportunity to save some money once 2.0 is out the door.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Update: &lt;/b&gt; We’re going to be extending the discount until Dec 31, 2019 due to the delayed release of 1.80.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;mobile&quot;&gt;Mobile&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mobile app has been significantly reworked and now feels more like a native app.  Navigation works properly and
also works amazingly well on a tablet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any feedback on our tablet app please reach out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This version will form the basis of our Android app which we plan on shipping in early 2020.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;spaces-within-tags&quot;&gt;Spaces within Tags&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spaces within tags are now fully supported.  This includes both folders and regular tags.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was hesitant to add this feature because then our tags wouldn’t be compatible with other systems like Twitter but
so many people requested this functionality that it’s probably very important moving forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;full-changelog&quot;&gt;Full Changelog&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Fixed bug with tablets now showing the pricing plan&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;removed outline on MacOS for tree nodes on the sidebar.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Dramatically improved our mobile and tablet apps.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Fixed bug where PHZ files were breaking with iframes that were invalid.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Changed #annotations and #stats URLs so that they are /annotations and /stats 
as we’re going to migrate to anchors for sub-screens for history.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Fixed privacy policy URL in login page&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Tags can now contain spaces and hyphens&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Semaphore now used for Windows disk writes.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Removed some unused libraries&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Upgrades to latest firebase&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">We have a new version of Polar out with some really interesting features.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Polar 1.70 - New Folders Sidebar, Improved Saving of Annotations, and Electron 7.0.</title><link href="https://getpolarized.io/2019/12/11/1-70-Folder-Exporting-Electron-7.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Polar 1.70 - New Folders Sidebar, Improved Saving of Annotations, and Electron 7.0." /><published>2019-12-11T08:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2019-12-11T08:00:00-08:00</updated><id>https://getpolarized.io/2019/12/11/1-70-Folder-Exporting-Electron-7</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://getpolarized.io/2019/12/11/1-70-Folder-Exporting-Electron-7.html">&lt;p&gt;Polar 1.70 is out! Lots of big changes in this release!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know I promised you guys that we would create a video for each release but I can’t create
one for 1.70 just now as I’m trying to rush it out to fix an issue with Google authentication
(more below).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Normally emergency releases I will do a small point release but this release changed a great 
deal and I think it’s a reasonable trade-off to get it out the door.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;new-sidebar&quot;&gt;New Sidebar&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;folder--tag-creation&quot;&gt;Folder / Tag Creation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sidebar code has been significantly refactored to be far far more usable.  You can read
more in-depth about &lt;a href=&quot;https://getpolarized.io/docs/folders.html&quot;&gt;how folders work in our documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a nutshell, we now have more explicit folders which can be created ahead of time by the user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This ended up confusing new users as they were confused how to work with tags.  They didn’t 
realize you first had to create tags/folders on documents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you can just right click the sidebar and click “Create Folder” or “Create Tag” and you’ll 
be prompted for the value of the new tag, and it will be created.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally there’s a “+” dropdown in the sidebar so it’s more discoverable for new users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;filtering&quot;&gt;Filtering&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now the sidebar code has a filter box at the top where you can type in text to filter 
the tags shown.  This works really well for selecting a tag that you know by name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can just select the filter, type the tag, then click the tag.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This became more important as we added improved support for tags and people are creating
more and more tags.  We don’t want to have tag overload!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;saving-annotations&quot;&gt;Saving Annotations&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of our users want to take their annotations and save them to external files.  They’re 
doing this to make it easy to share annotations with others but also for scripts or 
migrating into a document that they might be editing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One glaring omission was that the annotation view didn’t allow you to save annotations to 
a file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now there’s a “…” to the right where you can click “Download annotation as” to save the 
files locally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m trying to migrate away from calling this process “exporting” as we don’t have a 
corresponding “import.”  The Polar desktop app itself is basically it’s own export.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want a raw backup of your data on the desktop app it’s already done for you - it’s
just your .polar directory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, some users have noted some reasonable concern to feel more in charge of their
backups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m going to add an option to perform backups directly in Polar in the future just so 
users can have more piece of mind that their data is safe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;electron-70&quot;&gt;Electron 7.0&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This release also migrates us to Electron 7.0.  I’ve been wanting to do this for a while
but the Electron releases are usually a big migration.  This was forced on us by a change
Google made with their authentication which blocked Electron releases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Electron 7.0 adds a ton of new features for better integration into the OS so this should
be an improvement across the board in terms of usability, reliability, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;whats-next&quot;&gt;What’s Next&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next we’re going to focus on a 1.80 release. 2.0 is going to come out soon but I need to 
switch back to working on mobile support as this is very important for mobile flashcard 
review.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;full-changelog&quot;&gt;Full Changelog&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the full changelog for this release:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;features&quot;&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Migration to Electron 7.1.4&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Flagged items are now bold.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;odd/even coloring in the document list / table.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;usability: the sidebar has been significantly redesigned
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;”+” button for adding tags and folders&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;context menu for adding tags and folders&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;remove tag from docs&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;usability: expand/collapse of folders now works now.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;UI: better UI filter control.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;usability: you can now see the folders a file is within in the document repository&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;usability: you can now export annotations from the annotations view.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;usability: double click of comments or flashcards edits them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;fixes&quot;&gt;Fixes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Fix for Google authentication issues due to exposing Electron in User Agent and confused
Google.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Reading and review for older items would fail due to schema changes.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;ChromeOS is now a desktop platform&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Upgrade account button now works.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Improved text in suggestions dialog.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The user suggestions dialog is centered.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;usability: Fixed an issue where if the user accidentally hit ‘r’ the document would rotate and people
couldn’t figure out how to revert.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Polar 1.70 is out! Lots of big changes in this release!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Dark Mode by Default - 95% Prefer Dark over Light Mode</title><link href="https://getpolarized.io/2019/11/25/Dark-Mode-Should-Be-The-Default-With-95-Percent-Preferring-it-Over-Light-Mode.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dark Mode by Default - 95% Prefer Dark over Light Mode" /><published>2019-11-25T08:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2019-11-25T08:00:00-08:00</updated><id>https://getpolarized.io/2019/11/25/Dark-Mode-Should-Be-The-Default-With-95-Percent-Preferring-it-Over-Light-Mode</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://getpolarized.io/2019/11/25/Dark-Mode-Should-Be-The-Default-With-95-Percent-Preferring-it-Over-Light-Mode.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid border border-dark rounded&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/KSK0R75.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;dark-mode-by-default---95-prefer-dark-over-light-mode&quot;&gt;Dark Mode by Default - 95% Prefer Dark over Light Mode&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing that’s kept coming up when talking to Polar users is that we should implement dark mode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s quickly become one of our top requested features.  I think it’s about #3 right now in our new feature roadmap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem is that it’s a lot of work to build two skins (light and dark) so I had a thought: what if we only had one
theme and what if it was dark mode?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.discordapp.com/light-theme-redeemed-c541b7ab13e9&quot;&gt;Turns out Discord looked into the same thing:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;As of this writing, the percentage of Discord users on light theme is in the single digits — and not even the higher ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;… so single digits.  I’d call this about 95%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now this might not be clean data as Discord defaults to dark. Users would have to specifically pick the light theme after installing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further, their light mode wasn’t really ideal for a long time (which they admit) so this might have pushed users to 
dark mode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IntelliJ actually DOES require the user to pick from light/dark during onboarding and I would LOVE to see their data 
since they have a large user base.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;polling-polar-users&quot;&gt;Polling Polar Users&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve built into Polar a feature where we can poll our users and we asked them the same question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s currently sitting around 92% of people preferring dark mode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We asked the same question on Twitter and we’re polling around 82% right now (though with fewer users reporting).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;If you could only use one theme for polar, light them or dark theme (granted it&amp;#39;s not implemented yet), which one would you go with?&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; POLAR - Personal knowledge repository (@getpolarized) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/getpolarized/status/1197388523545845760?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;November 21, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;readability&quot;&gt;Readability&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main goal of Polar is to provide an amazing reading experience for our users. Not just in tools but it should extend
into the UX and usability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This, obviously, includes being able to read text.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s the point of all the other Polar features like tagging, annotation, spaced repetition, etc, if it burns your eyes
out of their sockets?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-just-one-theme&quot;&gt;Why Just One Theme?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It takes a lot of testing comparing the skins to make sure there is hasn’t been a regression.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And what’s worse, you can’t really run integration testing on theme colors as a lot of this is just aesthetic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The one theme idea, right now is mostly just a thought experiment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not planning on ditching light mode.  At least until I can confirm that no one is actually using it.  However, if we
can get to a point where it’s easily maintained maybe we would support both.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;pain-and-sleep-issues&quot;&gt;Pain and Sleep Issues&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think part of the issue here is that light mode can actually cause pain and sleep issues for some people. Having 
your retina’s burned out just before bed isn’t the best feeling and reading text for long term is definitely easier 
in dark mode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;new-apps-as-dark-by-default&quot;&gt;New Apps as Dark by Default&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This brings up a BIG issue though.  If you’re build a new app it should probably be dark by default.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In retrospect we should have gone dark to begin with but I can’t go back in time and change that now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, if I were building a new app from the ground up, I would make it dark-mode by default.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;… so we’re going to eventually have a dark mode.  We have a working prototype but just need a bit more time.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Polar 1.60 - Preparing for 2.0</title><link href="https://getpolarized.io/2019/11/20/1-60-Preparing-for-2-0.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Polar 1.60 - Preparing for 2.0" /><published>2019-11-20T08:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2019-11-20T08:00:00-08:00</updated><id>https://getpolarized.io/2019/11/20/1-60-Preparing-for-2-0</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://getpolarized.io/2019/11/20/1-60-Preparing-for-2-0.html">&lt;p&gt;Another big release is out to help prepare us for 2.0.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the changes here are small to moderate features and improving stability but there have also been a lot of library 
updates too which were important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;prompting-for-premium-and-locked-features&quot;&gt;Prompting for Premium and Locked Features&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the big changes in this release is that we’re now requiring that users upgrade for features in premium 
for which (in the past) we weren’t requiring an upgrade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This might mean at this point you will need to upgrade to premium if you depend on one of these features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;features&quot;&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The sidebar no longer shows the color for the buttons unless you hover over them.  The colors 
are also more muted to help not distract more when using the annotation sidebar.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Flashcards stats in the mobile app now work.  This way you can do a review and them immediately see the size of your
queue and also the number of tasks completed.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Ability to revise the text of a text highlight.  This was requested by a number of users due to some annotations 
having hyphens or errors in representation of mathematical formulas.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Big refactor of the context menu so that range selection and context menus work properly.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Multi-selection for deletes implemented.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;The context menus now have icons&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Ability to remove items from folders via right click&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Bronze now officially required for reading stats and recommended tags&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Major refactor of how text selection works using the new modern text layer code in pdf.js which has 
been a major complaint since 1.0.  Excited to finally have this fixed!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;fixes&quot;&gt;Fixes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Fixed issue with Polar builds not working on MacOS Catalina.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Upgrade to latest electron-builder so that we can have MacOS Catalina&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Fixed bug where sometimes exceptions were swallowed and not properly reported.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Updated Firebase to hopefully fix some bugs with latency and exceptions..&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Fixed delete dialogs as they were using older code…&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Merged branch for image optimization.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Fixed alignment of headers in the doc repo&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Fixed bad bug with stats for spaced repetition queue not being computed accurately.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Improved performance of doc table when selecting items.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The document repository view is now much faster and context menus no longer have a ‘gap’
which wouldn’t trigger the menu.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Now using larger buttons in the UI&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Show the front + back of cards when we ‘show answer’&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Another big release is out to help prepare us for 2.0.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Building Polar’s Product Market Fit Engine</title><link href="https://getpolarized.io/2019/11/11/Building-Polar-Product-Market-Fit-Engine.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Building Polar's Product Market Fit Engine" /><published>2019-11-11T20:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2019-11-11T20:00:00-08:00</updated><id>https://getpolarized.io/2019/11/11/Building-Polar-Product-Market-Fit-Engine</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://getpolarized.io/2019/11/11/Building-Polar-Product-Market-Fit-Engine.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid border border-dark rounded&quot; src=&quot;https://getpolarized.io//assets/screenshots/2019-11-document-view.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;building-polars-productmarket-fit-engine&quot;&gt;Building Polar’s Product/Market Fit Engine&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the past month or so I’ve been revamping Polar’s product-market-fit engine to help understand our users and to
prioritize feature requests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More importantly, it’s helping me build a product for the long-term based on science rather than whim.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wouldn’t it be great if we could build a engine that could systematically build a product roadmap but also help ensure 
that we’re building something that users actually want?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-field-of-dreams-fallacy&quot;&gt;The Field of Dreams Fallacy&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the movie &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NOPTByHw5RA&quot;&gt;Field of Dreams&lt;/a&gt;, (spoiler alert…) the protagonist hears a
voice that tells him to build a baseball field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later in the movie, after the field is built (and spending all of his family’s money in the process), thousands of people
arrive out of nowhere, bringing in money to help save his farm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In reality, this almost never happens.  Apps that explode and take off virally are very rare and the most successful
viral apps are actually the 4th or 5th attempt by the founders to get something to take off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The truth of the matter is that it’s very difficult to build a highly successful app and when you do there might
not actually be a customer acquisition model that actually works well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many startups and open source projects have an amazing product but can’t find users because they don’t have an
affordable customer acquisition channel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, how do we solve this problem?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;productmarket-fit&quot;&gt;Product/Market Fit&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Product/Market fit (PMF) is the idea that you’ve both found a market (a pool of users that want to buy and use your 
product) as well as a product that resonates with them and actually solves their problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the holy grail.  If you can nail this you’re going to have happy customers/users.  They’re going to tell their 
friends, you’re going to find new users just by word of mouth, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More importantly, they won’t churn.  Specifically, they’re actually going to use your product and keep coming back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Churn is the idea that people check out your product, then never return.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best way to reduce churn is to build something that people actually want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is where the PMF engine comes into play.  It provides a scientific framework for listening to customers and 
bootstrapping to PMF.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;using-science-and-statistics-to-hit-productmarket-fit&quot;&gt;Using Science and Statistics to Hit Product/Market Fit.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a scientist and it’s how I see the world. If I can’t quantify something with statistics I can’t 
improve it over time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A scientific approach to actually running a company/startup/project is going to be profoundly superior than just throwing
darts at a board.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://theleanstartup.com/&quot;&gt;The Lean Startup&lt;/a&gt; was the first book that I read that really put this at the forefront.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, &lt;a href=&quot;https://firstround.com/review/how-superhuman-built-an-engine-to-find-product-market-fit/&quot;&gt;Superhuman pushed this idea further&lt;/a&gt; with
the idea of actually using user feedback in a more scientific manner to nail PMF.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The central focus is to improve your features set for users who already love (and preferably pay for) your product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;make-something-people-love&quot;&gt;Make Something People Love&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.paulgraham.com/13sentences.html&quot;&gt;Paul Graham’s observation&lt;/a&gt; that you should first make a small group of users love you is a very important insight:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Ideally you want to make large numbers of users love you, but you can’t expect to hit that right away. Initially you
have to choose between satisfying all the needs of a subset of potential users, or satisfying a subset of the needs of
all potential users. Take the first. It’s easier to expand userwise than satisfactionwise. And perhaps more importantly,
it’s harder to lie to yourself. If you think you’re 85% of the way to a great product, how do you know it’s not 70%? Or
10%? Whereas it’s easy to know how many users you have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Users that are insanely happy with your product are more likely to recommend it to others, give you money, give you good reviews, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Users are who are only moderately interested in your product are going to provide you significantly less value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They’re significantly less likely to upgrade, less likely to be loyal if your product has a small issue, more likely to
stop using your product, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;talk-to-your-users&quot;&gt;Talk to your Users&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Build out a meaningful set of user interview questions to gain important insight about your app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actually &lt;em&gt;talk&lt;/em&gt; to your users.  No email.  Talk to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For Polar I setup a &lt;a href=&quot;https://calendly.com/&quot;&gt;Calendly&lt;/a&gt; form so that they could just pick a slot. I then tied it to &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/33W6LsC&quot;&gt;Zoom&lt;/a&gt; so
that each user could pick a time that works for them and that worked out well with my schedule.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then setup a script to send off 10 emails at a time to our users inviting them to time that works for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I find that since only about 10% agree to a user interview I just keep sending out emails until my calendar has enough
user interviews scheduled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Try to target about 3-5x per week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;user-polls&quot;&gt;User Polls&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OK.  I know I said to talk to your users.  But don’t JUST talk to them.  Some don’t have time but still have valuable 
feedback.  Take a modified version of your user interview questions and create a &lt;a href=&quot;http://referral.typeform.com/mteHQSg&quot;&gt;Typeform&lt;/a&gt; that
users can complete in less than 1 minute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use a lot of open ended questions.  Ask for data points too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;avoiding-survivor-bias&quot;&gt;Avoiding Survivor Bias&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the main issues is that most of the people who reply to our survey’s tend to be people that really like Polar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem is that this doesn’t help me solve issues that are causing potential users to churn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find this subset of users and reach out to them directly and talk to them. Pay them if you have too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This can be valuable insight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;feature-prioritization&quot;&gt;Feature Prioritization&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s where the main value comes from and that’s customized feature priority to help you nail PMF and make your users
insanely happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the most important part though - do not worry about making everyone happy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of your users aren’t going to like the app. Maybe you just don’t work well on their favorite platform. Maybe you’re
missing a key feature that’s not really on your roadmap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It doesn’t matter.  If they don’t value your product don’t value their features request and feedback as highly as other users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you do you’re going to be optimizing for building a &lt;em&gt;general&lt;/em&gt; product and we need to focus on landing a beachhead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We need to figure out some subset of users that are insanely addicted to your product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;technical-difficulty&quot;&gt;Technical Difficulty&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not all features are equal in terms of complexity.  Some you can bang out in 1-2 hours and others require months
of planning and work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This needs to be factored into our planning or we might be working on the wrong things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;customer-demand&quot;&gt;Customer Demand&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now score the customer demand but segment based on how they feel about your product.  There are a few ways to do this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The easiest is to segment. FIXME..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;impact&quot;&gt;Impact&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is slightly controversial but sometimes it’s important to ignore your customers and implement a feature that will
have greater long term impact on the company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, if you have two features, but one of those features causes dramatically increased user retention, go with 
this second feature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These type of features will yield higher revenue in the long term which means you can have the financial resources
to build out the rest of your feature set.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;prioritize-features-by-easy-of-implementation&quot;&gt;Prioritize features by easy of implementation&lt;/h2&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Polar 1.50 - Spaced Repetition, Better Incremental Reading and Plans for 2.0</title><link href="https://getpolarized.io/2019/11/11/1-50-Spaced-Repetition-Better-Incremental-Reading-and-Plans-for-2-0.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Polar 1.50 - Spaced Repetition, Better Incremental Reading and Plans for 2.0" /><published>2019-11-11T08:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2019-11-11T08:00:00-08:00</updated><id>https://getpolarized.io/2019/11/11/1-50-Spaced-Repetition-Better-Incremental-Reading-and-Plans-for-2-0</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://getpolarized.io/2019/11/11/1-50-Spaced-Repetition-Better-Incremental-Reading-and-Plans-for-2-0.html">&lt;p&gt;Polar 1.50 was just released and will be rolling out to everyone in a staged over the next week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is one of the biggest releases we’ve had in a long time and will be the foundation for 2.0.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;whats-in-this-release&quot;&gt;What’s In This Release&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now let’s get into what we’ve changed in this release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;improved-incremental-reading-and-spaced-repetition&quot;&gt;Improved Incremental Reading and Spaced Repetition&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of this release we conducted about 30 user interviews and one clear trend was that users needed and wanted a
better mobile experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The previous version of our mobile app was alpha at best and was just meant to be a standby until we had it fully ported
over to mobile and tablet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is going to take longer than I had hoped but dove tails into the long term of Polar being a spaced repetition platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve rebuild the mobile app and integrated native flashcard review into Polar directly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anki functionality and sync will keep improving of course and will not be deprecated.  In fact, we have a few more 
features we’re working on for Anki and will be enabling them in the coming weeks via feature flags at first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s now a ‘start review’ button in the annotations view that allows you to review your flashcards directly in Polar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;incremental-reading&quot;&gt;Incremental Reading&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of this we now have incremental reading and review of your annotations on mobile via spaced repetition schedules.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The intervals for incremental reading are longer for flashcards (1d, 4d, and 8d) and the system was designed to work
well with review on the mobile app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;new-mobile-app-redesign&quot;&gt;New Mobile App Redesign&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of the full mobile app redesign the new experience should be completely smooth and ready for production use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to improve it a bit more to work completely offline.  Firebase has some amazing cache/offline-first features 
where queries and data can be written and re-sync’d when you come back online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This has interesting opportunities for reviewing your reading and flashcards when not connected to the Internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;stats-for-flashcards&quot;&gt;Stats for Flashcards&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid border border-dark rounded&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/rjhlQLY.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This version now adds stats for flashcards including total completed, queue size, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;paid-on-mobile&quot;&gt;Paid on Mobile&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mobile flashcard review will be a paid feature in 2.0 when on mobile.  It will work for free on the desktop app
but if you want to review on mobile you will need a premium account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;annotation-bar-color-updates&quot;&gt;Annotation Bar color updates&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The annotation bar now has 5 main colors (up from 3) when selecting text for a highlight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;only-stable-features&quot;&gt;Only Stable Features&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re going to take the position of only enabling stable features from now on. For new users to Polar this was confusing
when they would see something like groups (even if it had a ‘beta’ flag on it) and I want them to have a good initial&lt;br /&gt;
experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From now on we will be enabling new (and not yet ready) features via feature flags that developers or beta testers 
can turn on manually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;documentation-and-website-updates&quot;&gt;Documentation and Website Updates&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our documentation is being reworked now to update the changes needed for 2.0.  I’m going to try to get more press for 
2.0 so this will mean a lot of new user seeing Polar for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;full-list-of-changes-in-15010&quot;&gt;Full List of Changes in 1.50.10&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Statistics now shown for flashcards when the user is using spaced repetition&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;No more hamburger menu in the sidebar.  All options are now flat in the desktop UI and more discoverable.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Using proper MacOS system font along with Robot everywhere else including android devices.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;New documentation rework and will be improving this long term.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Added two more colors to the annotation bar. Was frequently requested by our users so just added it.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Flashcards now inherit the text of the annotation when being created to avoid double copy / pasting of text.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Mobile now a supported platform and designed for spaced repetition.  This will get us moving on mobile until
we can build out a real/full reading platform there.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The header and footer in the doc repo is fixed now and don’t move as you scroll.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Fixed bug with drag and drop and working with items from the second page of results.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Flashcard reviewer now integrated along with our normal spaced repetition.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Annotation reviewer spaced repetition system finally integrated into Polar&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;More work on mobile including disabling some features when using the app.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Active filters are now light blue so that users know they have filters enabled.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Color and annotation type filters now work.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Fixed bug with the root folders having the wrong counts&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;whats-next-and-plans-for-20&quot;&gt;What’s Next and Plans for 2.0&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This release is basically the foundation for 2.0.  There are a few more features / changes to make before 2.0 is ready.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have to improve our documentation a bit more and we have a few more fixes and changes that are still pending.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;updated-annotation-sidebar&quot;&gt;Updated Annotation Sidebar&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m looking at improving the annotation sidebar to add features like filtering by text (search basically), tagging documents
directly (vs having to jump back to the document repository), and other options like archiving, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;better-pricing-models&quot;&gt;Better Pricing Models&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m working on better pricing models for students and those outside the United States in developing countries.  Charging
$4.99 per month to someone in India/Laos doesn’t seem fair considering the differing values of currencies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m also investigating yearly accounts as I think there’s a psychological advantage for students to buy in 1-2 year 
increments as it seems many people really dislike monthly payments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;better-keyboard-bindings&quot;&gt;Better Keyboard Bindings&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re investigating bringing on board better keyboard bindings.  It didn’t make it to this release because we have to
do a big dependency management update (React) and I wanted to get a stable release out the door.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Polar 1.50 was just released and will be rolling out to everyone in a staged over the next week.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Polar 1.40 - Tags in the sidebar, Drag and Drop Folders, and more!</title><link href="https://getpolarized.io/2019/10/24/1-40-Tags-sidebar-drag-and-drop-folders.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Polar 1.40 - Tags in the sidebar, Drag and Drop Folders, and more!" /><published>2019-10-24T09:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-10-24T09:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://getpolarized.io/2019/10/24/1-40-Tags-sidebar-drag-and-drop-folders</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://getpolarized.io/2019/10/24/1-40-Tags-sidebar-drag-and-drop-folders.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid border border-dark rounded&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/HEKJEE2.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;polar-140---tags-in-the-sidebar-drag-and-drop-folders-and-more&quot;&gt;Polar 1.40 - Tags in the sidebar, Drag and Drop Folders, and more!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Polar 1.40 is now available.  This release includes a number of new features upgrades and stability improvements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, I should apologize for the slower release cycle lately.  I’ve been working on a number of internal refactors
to Polar to help us scale moving forward.  Among these was a pretty large refactor into a ‘monorepo’ using submodules
to make Polar much easier to manage moving forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will enable a number of new features which below.  It’s already improved our speed of development now that we’ve
mostly finished the migration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;whats-in-this-release&quot;&gt;What’s In This Release&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now let’s get into what we’ve changed in this release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tags-on-the-sidebar&quot;&gt;Tags on the Sidebar&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We now have tags (not just folders) on the sidebar.  You can see the tags and the number of documents with the given
tag.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This also works for the annotation view too and you can see the tag counts there as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clicking on the tag will load the tag in the right pane.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;drag-and-drop-of-folders&quot;&gt;Drag and Drop of Folders&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can now drag and drop documents on to folders or tag.  Dragging the document will add the the folder or tag to the 
dropped document.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This won’t yet work for annotations as we have to upgrade our viewer for this to happen but it’s on the roadmap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;fixed-bad-firebase-authentication-bug&quot;&gt;Fixed Bad Firebase Authentication Bug&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We fixed an issue with the desktop version of Polar (running on Electron) where it would intermittently fail to 
authenticate to Firebase when trying to sync to cloud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was really tough to track down and I apologize to anyone bitten by this bug. It would only impact some users and
only some small percentage of the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;library-upgrades&quot;&gt;Library Upgrades&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve upgraded to the latest versions of firebase, pdfjs, jszip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;whats-next&quot;&gt;What’s Next&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the short/medium term we’re working on improving these issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;improved-folders&quot;&gt;Improved Folders&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many users have been confused with how folders work and in retrospect I can see why.  We shipped with a basic interface
which was somewhat non-standard so it wasn’t really possible to figure out how it worked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re going to add some UI changes to make this more accessible including a ‘+’ (create folder) button and the ability
to create folders, and then drag files into them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;stable-groups-release&quot;&gt;Stable Groups Release&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re working on improving groups which are only about 80% complete.  I’m hoping that the drag and drop interface will
make them easier to use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m struggling with some UI issues here so my plan is to bring in a designer to help me understand the challenges I
have with making it easy to use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;new-version-of-capture&quot;&gt;New Version of Capture&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re working on a redesign of the way web capture works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Web capture is the ability for Polar to take a web document in HTML and store it within Polar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Too many users are reporting that capture fails a significant percentage of the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further, capture doesn’t currently support adblock, readability, or other chrome/firefox extensions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new design will allow it to work directly within the extension within the browser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The intention is to target the web extension API which will mean it will work on Chrome, Firefox, Edge, and Safari.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can’t commit to supporting all four major browsers out of the door but that’s the goal.  We have about 90% of our
users on Chrome but Firefox and Safari are definitely important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;doi-lookup-and-extended-metadata&quot;&gt;DOI Lookup and Extended Metadata&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re working on supporting more 3rd party metadata lookup APIs.  Initially we will support just lookup of public
documents via DOI using &lt;a href=&quot;https://unpaywall.org/&quot;&gt;unpaywall&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will allow you to enter a DOI, fetch the document into your repository, and store the extended metadata.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ll also support resolving the metadata if the PDF has a DOI in stored in its metadata.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will also serve as the basis for enhanced citation management.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The long term plans are to support the Pubmed API and the Fatcat API provided by the Internet Archive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;thumbnails&quot;&gt;Thumbnails&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re planning on adding thumbnail previews for documents added to Polar.  This has been on the agenda for a while now
but is only just now possible due to some complexities regarding thumbnails and snapshots across operating systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think initially this might only work when cloud-sync is enabled but I’d like to get it to work on the desktop version
of Polar at some point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;electron-70&quot;&gt;Electron 7.0&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re going to migrate to Electron 7.0 now that it’s out. The major feature here is the updated Chrome backend but there
are some other nice stability improvements here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;freemium-vs-premium&quot;&gt;Freemium vs Premium&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re working on some other features in the background to the premium version of Polar including full-text search.  Some
of the citation management features will also be premium features like they are in other citation management tools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m also working on working other ways to get access to Polar premium for students and others in developing nations 
that might not be able to afford these tools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll be talking about these in the next few weeks.  Unfortunately, many of these features just flat out cost money 
including features like cross-device full-text search, OCR, text to speech, and other premium features I’m considering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;upgrading&quot;&gt;Upgrading&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want to make sure you’re on the right version of Polar?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;web&quot;&gt;Web&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re using the web version of Polar you’re probably running the latest version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;desktop&quot;&gt;Desktop&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re using a desktop app this release will be pushed to all users over the next week. If you’d like to see if
you’re already on the latest version just go to &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Help | About&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to upgrade earlier you can go to &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Help | Check for Updates&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What’s Next for Offline Web Capture of Web Pages in Polar</title><link href="https://getpolarized.io/2019/10/06/Whats-Next-For-Web-Capture.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What's Next for Offline Web Capture of Web Pages in Polar" /><published>2019-10-06T09:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-10-06T09:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://getpolarized.io/2019/10/06/Whats-Next-For-Web-Capture</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://getpolarized.io/2019/10/06/Whats-Next-For-Web-Capture.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/lLKEfKI.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;overview&quot;&gt;Overview&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since we shipped Polar we’ve been listening to feedback from our users as to the default behavior and functionality of 
web capture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Web capture (or just capture) is what we call converting an HTML page to a format that can be persisted and used within
Polar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This code started off as an advanced proof of concept but it had a few issues in practice that holds it back from 
perfectly solving the problem of offline web pages as documents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s what we’re working on in the background.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;epub&quot;&gt;EPUB&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EPUB will become the default format.  Internally, EPUB is just HTML and CSS and if we migrate web capture to use EPUB 
then this means we &lt;em&gt;also&lt;/em&gt; support EPUB as a primary file format in Polar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also means less code to debug since everything is EPUB.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re going to work on a converter to take our PHZ format and convert it to EPUB so that existing documents will 
convert in place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;based-on-web-extensions&quot;&gt;Based on Web Extensions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re going to migrate everything to a web extension.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means the native Electron capture will migrate to being completely browser based.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our goal is to support Chrome, Firefox, and Safari extensions during this process as our Firefox extension is nearly 
finished.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The advantages here are the ability to use regular chrome extensions like uBlock, Ad Block Pro, Mercury Reader, or Easy Reader.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new extension will completely bundle the pages resources and send them to the Polar cloud or desktop app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;fluid-layout&quot;&gt;Fluid Layout.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new format will not require a fixed document size like the previous version.  This was needed due to the layout
algorithm for placing highlights.  The new version should support placing highlights based on text.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One UI change might be that area highlights for HTML documents will anchor to images since the flow can change this 
means that an area you select might move when you resize.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;mobile-and-tablet-support&quot;&gt;Mobile and Tablet Support&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we’ve migrated to EPUB as a backend, captured content will work on mobile and tablet devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re also going to have capture work on mobile by sending the raw URL to the Polar cloud backend and having it 
perform the capture for you in the background.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This way capture will work on all devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;lightweight-capture-url-only&quot;&gt;Lightweight Capture (URL only)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re also going to work on lightweight capture where we store the URL only.  I think for a lot of users it might not
make sense to store 300k per document as part of Polar so storing just the URL and annotations will mean much 
lower storage requirements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;overview-1&quot;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think these issues will solve 95% of the initial problems we had with capture and make the entire platform much more
reliable.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Future of Polar Cloud Sync</title><link href="https://getpolarized.io/2019/10/05/Future-of-Polar-Cloud-Sync.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Future of Polar Cloud Sync" /><published>2019-10-05T09:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-10-05T09:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://getpolarized.io/2019/10/05/Future-of-Polar-Cloud-Sync</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://getpolarized.io/2019/10/05/Future-of-Polar-Cloud-Sync.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid&quot; src=&quot;https://getpolarized.io/assets/images/firebase-sync-scaled.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-future-of-polar-cloud-sync&quot;&gt;The Future of Polar Cloud Sync&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re going to be changing some features in the ‘local’ mode version of Polar and some new cloud features won’t be 
available in this mode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve tried to keep Polar’s local mode as full featured as possible but I’ve decided that this just isn’t possible 
moving forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New features like full-text search, machine learning, and other features won’t be available in local mode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll explain more below but please read the full post if you’re concerned or have any suggestions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;background&quot;&gt;Background&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Polar has three modes of operation.  Local, cloud, and web.  These are internal modes and you’ve probably never 
really thought of them before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you first install Polar on the desktop it’s local only. No files are written to the cloud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you login to cloud on the desktop, it goes into cloud mode and transparently syncs between local and the cloud
so that your local files are synchronized between all your devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The web mode is basically just the cloud mode bug without any local support.  It’s what you’re using when you login 
to the webapp or use Polar on tablet or desktop devices.  It has the same features as cloud mode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;offline&quot;&gt;Offline&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The local, cloud, and web modes don’t accurately portray offline functionality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All three modes will work in offline (and disconnected) mode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, if you’re using a tablet, and have Polar installed, and you’ve downloaded a PDF before, you can still open
it again and continue reading and annotating while it’s offline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What WILL NOT work is search and some of the features articulated below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;offline-vs-online-features&quot;&gt;Offline vs Online Features&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most core features of Polar will be designed to work offline.  Firebase itself has support for offline operation which
means our webapp, and mobile and tablet apps will work just fine while offline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;cloud-specific-features&quot;&gt;Cloud-specific Features&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some features won’t be ported to the desktop mode and will only work in cloud or web mode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt; &lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;local&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;cloud&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;web&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;full-text search&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;no&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;online&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;online&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;thumbnails for documents&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;no [1]&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;online&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;online&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;ML features like tags suggested from content&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;no&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;online&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;online&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;search for new documents using Arxiv / Pubmed&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;online [2]&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;online&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;online&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Probably not initially but perhaps in the future.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This will use a web service and will run your queries online but the PDFs and metadata will only be stored locally.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;motivation&quot;&gt;Motivation&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Features like full-text search and other machine learning (ML) features have been requested by our users for a while now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to add these features but they’re very complex and I can’t approach them as I would like adding a new UI button 
or something trivial.  Complex performance issues, scale, power utilization, all factor into this decision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;reasoning&quot;&gt;Reasoning&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mobile and tablet support are going to be a big part of Polar’s future.  After talking to our users it’s becoming 
very clear that we’d probably have 50% of our users using these devices if they weren’t locked down to just desktop
and the web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is by far the primary motivator for implementing these features in the cloud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can’t use Elasticsearch in mobile devices.  We can’t spin up tensor flow on your tablet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if we could the power requirements would be insane.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are dozens of APIs and features we can use with cloud APIs that just aren’t available any other way.  Thumbnails,
text to speech, OCR, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;portability&quot;&gt;Portability&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any code based on cloud infrastructure will work across all devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mobile, tablet, desktop. Android, iOS, MacOS, Windows, Linux.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we’re using Elasticsearch in the cloud it doesn’t matter which frontend device you’re using.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;complexity&quot;&gt;Complexity&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Supporting all platforms and operating systems for these features would be completely unworkable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;performance&quot;&gt;Performance&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if we could solve all the above the performance would be abysmal.  Importing a large document set could take 5-15 
minutes when using full-text indexing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Elasticsearch I can index your documents across 100 nodes in parallel and have it done 100x faster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;feature-set&quot;&gt;Feature Set&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Frameworks like Elasticsearch and Tensorflow are very powerful. We might be able to get away with using something else 
but for the most part it’s not going to be worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even simple features like language stemming aren’t really well documented in other desktop-only search libraries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;scale&quot;&gt;Scale&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving forward, I can bring in additional teams to easily manage these services on the backend.  This is going to help
grow the team and make sure you’re a satisfied user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;pricing-and-access&quot;&gt;Pricing and Access&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of these cloud features will cost money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have some ideas on how to keep things more affordable (and free) for students and freemium users but generally
speaking, users with larger repositories will have to pay to use these features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;… but believe me, it will be worth it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;unlocking-features&quot;&gt;Unlocking Features&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some features of Polar may be unlocked in the future and in that case, if you don’t want to use any cloud services, we
will just authenticate you and then allow you to opt out of cloud sync.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;backups--snapshots&quot;&gt;Backups / Snapshots&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will also allow us to support backups and snapshots of your data so that you can restore data directly from the 
cloud.  Google cloud storage is insanely cheap so the plan is to enable a simple export/import mechanism which will 
store your datastore directly on Google Cloud Storage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pricing for this is reasonable so we’re planning on taking regular backups for our users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;offline-first-and-data-privacy&quot;&gt;Offline First and Data Privacy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We generally support the “offline-first” movement to keep data out of cloud devices but it’s a very complicated subject.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some users don’t want any of their data in the cloud. Some are just concerned about which data providers are used.&lt;br /&gt;
Some users don’t care at all as long as it’s reasonably secure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One major issue is data storage location.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re going to improve our usability here by allowing the user to pick a primary location among the available Google 
datacenters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re going to support the United States and Western Europe.  &lt;a href=&quot;https://firebase.google.com/docs/firestore/locations&quot;&gt;Google’s Datacenters are located here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will help our users concerned about where they have their physical data stored.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We probably won’t have this soon but we’d like to have it done in the near term (3-12 months).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We won’t be able to provide any non-Google issues as we’re using their Firebase platform and don’t have plans to move away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;additional-features&quot;&gt;Additional Features&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cloud mode enables additional features as well including the ability to sync the URL of your document (or annotations)
to Anki so that the context for a flashcard is available with one click.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re just simply not able to implement features like this without some type of cloud backend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;default-mode&quot;&gt;Default Mode&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the future we will encourage users to use the cloud mode by default so that all features are enabled including sync.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In summary, Polar will continue to support local mode into the near future with limited features compared to full cloud
and web mode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re also going to encourage users to use cloud mode by default moving forward and will also allow you to pick your 
own datacenter and by default pick one closer to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the new cloud support we also intend on supporting advanced features like full-text search, machine learning, and 
backups.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry></feed>