<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://getpolarized.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://getpolarized.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-04-16T17:17:54-06:00</updated><id>https://getpolarized.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">POLAR - Easily manage your PDFs, web content, and notes.</title><subtitle>A powerful document manager for Mac, Windows, and Linux for managing web content, books, and notes and supports tagging, annotation, highlighting and keeps track of your reading progress.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">The anonymous story of a NYC resident at the frontlines of the COVID-19 pandemic</title><link href="https://getpolarized.io/2020/04/12/The-Anonymous-Story-Of-A-NYC-Resident-At-The-Frontlines-Of-The-COVID-19-Pandemic.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The anonymous story of a NYC resident at the frontlines of the COVID-19 pandemic" /><published>2020-04-12T10:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2020-04-12T10:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://getpolarized.io/2020/04/12/The-Anonymous-Story-Of-A-NYC-Resident-At-The-Frontlines-Of-The-COVID-19-Pandemic</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://getpolarized.io/2020/04/12/The-Anonymous-Story-Of-A-NYC-Resident-At-The-Frontlines-Of-The-COVID-19-Pandemic.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/eVZdJcC.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-anonymous-story-of-a-nyc-resident-at-the-frontlines-of-the-covid-19-pandemic&quot;&gt;The Anonymous Story Of A NYC Resident At The Frontlines Of The COVID-19 Pandemic&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The COVID-19 pandemic has significantly impacted all of our lives. NYC residents have been particularly hard stricken. As of April 10, the total number of confirmed cases is over 100,000, with almost seven thousand fatalities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had a rare chance to talk about the current situation to a anesthesiology resident in NYC. Sarah (name changed) is in her late twenties and a third year resident in a large hospital in NYC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-daily-struggle-is-pushing-everyone-to-the-limit&quot;&gt;The daily struggle is pushing everyone to the limit&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She spoke with us after  yet another 14 hour shift and is making food before crashing in her small one-bed room apartment in the Upper East Side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“As an anesthesiologist, you usually have two roles” Sarah starts, “you are an intensive care doctor, tending to the day to day work for your critical patients, as well as taking urgent calls for intubations”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Typically, a resident would do five intubations a day, maximum.. “That’s already a busy day. Now we’re doing an average of 20!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just like everybody in the hospital, intubation teams are being pushed to their limits these days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of the high patient numbers, hospitals have run out of space. “Normally, intubations are supposed to be done in a negative pressure rooms to minimize risks of infections. However, because it’s so busy, we’re doing it in a standard room with just a curtain around the patient’s bed. Next the patient is already the next one. No privacy, no containment.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;patients-are-sometimes-surprised-to-learn-they-are-infected&quot;&gt;Patients are sometimes surprised to learn they are infected&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Worsening matters, patients oftentimes don’t know they have the virus when the intubation team arrives. This means the team informs them as they start the intubation. Doctors who usually inform the patient beforehand are too busy attending to other patients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“When patients realize what’s going on, they try to frantically call family to tell them about the situation,” says Sarah.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Higher mortality because hospitals are past their limits&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Approximately 20% of cases get hospitalized, and 20% of those need intubation,” points out Sarah. “50% of those who get intubated die”. Of course, numbers vary significantly across age group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“In my opinion, the mortality rate is so high because we are past our limits and not capable to provide the level of care we normally would”, says Sarah.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously patients in the ICU need a lot of care which is why one nurse typically only takes care of no more than two ICU patients. 
“They need to be turned every two hours to avoid pressure sores, labs need to be taken every six hours, and a host of vital signs are constantly monitored to step in immediately if necessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, one nurse will take care of four patients on average. And we are still short on nurses. This means nurses with no or limited experience with critical care are being coached in the moment”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Nobody is getting turned every two hours. Nobody is doing PT. And keep in mind, the average intubation period is three weeks for those patients”, elaborates Sarah.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the worst cases, patients might wake up after intubation due to limited attention from nurses. Those patients oftentimes get agitated and self-extubate, which only worsens their situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last Tuesday, the Emergency Department had 16 patients on ventilators. “There was simply no space in the ICU. The ratio of patient to nurse was 13:1”, Sarah continues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This is a good hospital with a large critical care team. Despite that, we still might have to give a crash course to an orthopedic surgeon who never managed a ventilator before.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;medical-staff-are-holding-up-but-long-term-effects-are-unclear&quot;&gt;Medical staff are holding up but long-term effects are unclear&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We asked Sarah how she and hospital staff are impacted by the situation.
“I’m used to seeing patients with terminal illnesses. The hard part is knowing it’s impossible to provide them with the best care.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“However, we are not used to seeing young patients with no medical history in those situations.” Normally, patients who get intubated already have multiple illnesses. “But in the current situation, you see patients who are 41, no medical history, non-smokers, fighting for their lives”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is what hits especially young doctors the hardest. Sarah argues that the immediate impact on her mental health is very manageable. “My hospital is providing me with excellent support.” Mental health and wellness initiatives are available for doctors and hospital staff at no cost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“However, it’s impossible to predict what the long-term impact will be on all of us.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;supply-chain-of-equipment-is-still-intact&quot;&gt;Supply chain of equipment is still intact&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One very comforting observation is a never-ending supply of donations to hospitals. The hospital has enough personal protective equipment (PPE) and donations keep coming in. “I know not every hospital accepts direct donations. “Donations that can’t be accepted, we can keep for personal use”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On top of PPE donations, the hospital has been receiving donations of food and other daily necessities. “We had really, really good steak, salads, and pizza donated last week. Some even drop off wine to support us when we’re out of the hospital”, she says with a laugh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, hospitals are making sure that staff stay as safe as possible. “The reason for the cold trucks outside of hospitals is not that there’s no space in our morgues. But the morgues don’t accept patients infected with COVID-19 to avoid spread of the disease.”, she elaborates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bodies are then taken to be cremated. This, however, sometimes results in pushback from the families. “But cremation is essential to prevent the spread”, she explains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;number-of-new-cases-are-easing-up-in-nyc&quot;&gt;Number of new cases are easing up in NYC&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking ahead, the hope is that “this and last week are the peak in NYC. We are already seeing admissions slowing down.” However, it remains critically important to do everything possible to flatten the curve and slow down the spread.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One worry is a resurgence of cases once the lockdown is lifted. ”Realistically, we won’t get in the safe zone until we get a vaccine out – hopefully by September or October”, Sarah explains. “Some people are saying it might be seasonal. That would mean that even if we get a vaccine out, we might get it back in a few months”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;message-to-the-people&quot;&gt;Message to the people&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end, we ask Sarah if she has a message for us at home. Her response speaks volumes the spirit of New Yorkers (which we can 100% attest to after having lived there for a long time ourselves).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’m really thankful for the generosity the people have shown. We get donations en masse. Every day we get personal equipment, food, and other supplies”, Sarah responds. “Restaurants are delivering food for free. Those restaurants point out that they themselves received donations and instructions to prepare food for the hospitals around them.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We are all in this together, and I’m confident we’ll get through this stronger than before”.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How An Astronaut’s Experience Can Enable Us To Study Better From Home</title><link href="https://getpolarized.io/2020/03/30/How-An-Astronaut's-Experience-Can-Enable-Us-To-Study-Better-From-Home.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How An Astronaut's Experience Can Enable Us To Study Better From Home" /><published>2020-03-30T10:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2020-03-30T10:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://getpolarized.io/2020/03/30/How-An-Astronaut's-Experience-Can-Enable-Us-To-Study-Better-From-Home</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://getpolarized.io/2020/03/30/How-An-Astronaut's-Experience-Can-Enable-Us-To-Study-Better-From-Home.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/9iLF7UR.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;how-an-astronauts-experience-can-enable-us-to-study-better-from-home&quot;&gt;How An Astronaut’s Experience Can Enable Us To Study Better From Home&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of us are going into week 2 of studying and working remotely. Obviously, we humans are not made to stay in a confined space for a long time. That’s why it’s even more important to be deliberate about how we go about our daily lives. Here at &lt;a href=&quot;https://getpolarized.io&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Polar&lt;/a&gt;, we’re working on a tool to enable remote studying and knowledge management. We did want to take some time, however, to look at what else we can do to optimize our time at home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the subsequent post, we summarize key learnings from an astronaut’s experience in space. Back in 2015 / 2016, Scott Kelly spent nearly a year in space living on the ISS. In an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2020/03/21/opinion/scott-kelly-coronavirus-isolation.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;interview&lt;/a&gt; with the New York Times, he admits it “wasn’t always easy but I learned some things during my time up there”. His experience clearly shows that there is a way to make this productive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid border border-secondary&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/DRYuC2t.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;follow-a-routine&quot;&gt;Follow a routine&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Maintaining a plan will help you adjust to a different environment”, says Kelly. “On the space station, my time was scheduled tightly, from the moment I woke up to when I went to sleep”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that classes are remote, it’s easier to let a regular schedule slip. We see it ourselves. For example, the gym is closed and of course it’s harder to work out at home. However, keeping a set schedule will prevent us from slipping into a world where we end up only sitting on the couch, smoking weed, and eating unhealthy food. Hell, while you’re at it, this might be a good time to incorporate some good habits into your daily routine, like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mindful.org/how-to-meditate/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;meditation&lt;/a&gt; or the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VaMjhwFE1Zw&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Wim Hof method&lt;/a&gt;. And if you need some motivation, we have just the right &lt;a href=&quot;https://davidgoggins.com/book/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;book&lt;/a&gt; for you to get started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;pace-yourself&quot;&gt;Pace yourself&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“When you are living and working in the same place for days on end, work can have a way of taking over everything if you let it”, Kelly argues. “Living in space, I deliberately paced myself because I knew I was in it for the long haul.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many different ways to achieve that - reading a book, calling friends, or simply taking a nap. We see it ourselves all the time. There is always one more thing that needs to be done, always one additional discussion to be had. However, a refreshed mind is much more useful than an overworked and stressed one. So make sure you pace yourself.
On the flip side, make sure you don’t “pace yourself” too much. &lt;a href=&quot;https://shyamsankar.com/the-case-against-work-life-balance-owning-your-future&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;It’s interesting&lt;/a&gt; how people typically only state “it’s a marathon, not a sprint” to argue for more comfort, not of sustained excellence. If you want to achieve all your dreams, you simply have to put in the time. Of course while pacing yourself ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;spent-time-outside-while-keeping-social-distance&quot;&gt;Spent time outside (while keeping social distance)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the main advantages of living in the Bay Area is nature. Obviously, with every passing day, it’s becoming harder for me to spend time outside. But while it’s still possible, make sure you go out for walks and get some fresh air. Of course while maintaining the necessary social distance. In fact, while you’re at it, you might want to consider wearing a mask, even if just makeshift. There is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BoDwXwZXsDI&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;early indication&lt;/a&gt; that masks are a key part in fighting the spreading of the virus. So, do go outside. And be reasonable about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;focus-on-hobbies&quot;&gt;Focus on hobbies&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Duh. This is obvious but we tend to forget it in times of stress (like finals… or a pandemic). Usually, reading is a good hobby to pick up. Now you might argue you’re already reading a lot for school (and simplifying your reading and information management with &lt;a href=&quot;https://getpolarized.io&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Polar&lt;/a&gt; ;) ). That’s ok. Pick something else. I recently picked up cooking again. Whatever it is, make sure it gives you the timeout you need from your studies&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;start-journaling&quot;&gt;Start journaling&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NASA discovered that keeping a journal is one of the most effective activities to keep us sane. Interesting, huh? “Even if you don’t wind up writing a book based on your journal like I did, writing about your days will help put your experiences in perspective and let you look back later on what this unique time in history has meant”, Kelly shares. There are many different versions of journaling out there. I’ve been doing my own version for over 10 years and absolutely love it. While you’re at it, definitely add affirmations to it. Then go out and kick butt achieving those goals you tell yourself during the affirmations. Well, stay inside and achieve those goals ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;take-time-to-connect&quot;&gt;Take time to connect&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Isolation is damaging not only to our mental health, but to our physical health as well, especially our immune system”, Kelly warns. Make sure you regularly connect with loved ones and close friends. Now might even be a good time to reconnect with this one person you’ve lost contact with a while back… or reconnect with your ex you still think of. Melissa, how are you doing…? ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;listen-to-expert-voices&quot;&gt;Listen to expert voices&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And finally… listen to experts. “Living in space taught me a lot about the importance of trusting the advice of people who knew more than I did about their subjects”, Kelly shares. Given how much misinformation is actively being spread these days about the coronavirus (did you &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.com/news/world-51735367&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;hear&lt;/a&gt; how garlic can prevent the spread of coronavirus?), make sure you listen to people with authority in the subject.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Polar 1.100.13 - Tags for Annotations</title><link href="https://getpolarized.io/2020/03/27/Polar-1-100-13-Tags-For-Annotations.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Polar 1.100.13 - Tags for Annotations" /><published>2020-03-27T10:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2020-03-27T10:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://getpolarized.io/2020/03/27/Polar-1-100-13-Tags-For-Annotations</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://getpolarized.io/2020/03/27/Polar-1-100-13-Tags-For-Annotations.html">&lt;p&gt;Polar 1.100.12 is now available on the web for all desktop users and will be rolling out over the next week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-responsive embed-responsive-16by9&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe class=&quot;embed-responsive-item&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/6M6jNlairGc&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tags-for-annotations&quot;&gt;Tags for Annotations&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main feature of this release is tags for annotations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This has been frequently requested by users and we finally were able to devote 
the time to making sure it was implemented properly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;stability&quot;&gt;Stability&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course we’ve also fixed a number of bugs in this release including a bad one
that sometimes prevented the UI from updating when working with annotations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;whats-next&quot;&gt;What’s Next&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re working on moving the entire platform over to React including the PDF 
viewer.  Once this is complete we’ll be able to quickly finish implementing 
EPUB, dark mode, and some improvements to our chrome extension to enable 
annotation and capture directly in the browser for web content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will also meant that tablet and phone support can come online as 2.0 is 
being designed with mobile support in mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;full-changelog&quot;&gt;Full Changelog&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;annotations in the annotation view are now sorted by ‘last updated’ not the
creation time.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;annotations can have tags&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Polar 1.100.12 is now available on the web for all desktop users and will be rolling out over the next week.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">17 tips for crushing it with Anki while studying remotely</title><link href="https://getpolarized.io/2020/03/27/17-Tips-For-Using-Anki-While-Studying-From-Home.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="17 tips for crushing it with Anki while studying remotely" /><published>2020-03-27T10:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2020-03-27T10:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://getpolarized.io/2020/03/27/17-Tips-For-Using-Anki-While-Studying-From-Home</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://getpolarized.io/2020/03/27/17-Tips-For-Using-Anki-While-Studying-From-Home.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/FeMzRL1.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;17-tips-for-crushing-it-with-anki-while-studying-remotely&quot;&gt;17 tips for crushing it with Anki while studying remotely&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the last few years, Anki has become a staple for us when learning with flashcards. Usually, we annotate our readings in &lt;a href=&quot;https://getpolarized.io/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Polar&lt;/a&gt;, then auto-convert those annotations into flashcards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest reason I love using Anki is that it simplifies learning by reminding me when to repeat flashcards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Polar supports both textbooks and webpages, which made it a key part of our workflow for both schoolwork and personal learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below, we are summarizing our key learnings for Anki. For most part, these tips also work for other spaced repetition platforms, like Quizlet or Supermemo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;1-understand-how-spaced-repetition-works&quot;&gt;1. Understand how spaced repetition works&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A tool is only as useful as we make it for us, so make sure you understand how &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spaced_repetition&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;spaced reptition&lt;/a&gt; works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key is to why repeated review is crucial. That will avoid reverting back to the standard approach - wait until a week before the exam and freak out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid border border-secondary&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/otv7GF0.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;2-speed-up-flashcard-creation&quot;&gt;2. Speed up flashcard creation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Creating flashcards takes time which it shouldn’t have to. That’s why we use Polar to speed things up. Polar allows you to auto-convert annotations into flashcards. They can easily be synced with Anki for studying&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, Polar supports incremental reading and reading progress tracking. That’s crucial to manage multiple readings and continue where you left off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid border border-secondary&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/rbAwfR6.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;3-maximize-impact-of-active-recall&quot;&gt;3. Maximize impact of active recall&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should also understand why &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Active_recall&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;active recall&lt;/a&gt; is so important.
Active recall is a principle of efficient learning. It claims the need to actively stimulate memory during the learning process. It contrasts with passive review, in which the learning material is processed passively (e.g. by reading, watching, etc.). For example, reading a text about George Washington, with no further action, is a passive review. Answering the question “Who was the first US President?”, is active recall.
Essentially you want everything to be a question and you want to have to think of the answer. It’s this thinking process which allows your brain to map weights to specific neurons and actually retain information.
Don’t give leading questions or hints to the answer. If you don’t know the questions that’s fine. Just mark that on the card so it’s brought up again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;4-build-a-habit&quot;&gt;4. Build a habit&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You couldn’t sit down at the end of the month and brush your teeth for 2-3 hours to make up for not brushing would you?
The same is true for using spaced repetition - it should be a daily process of 15 - 60 min. Do it while you’re commuting. Or bored. Or even worse - waiting in line at the DMV.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid border border-secondary&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/fwgmZOX.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;5-aim-for-90-difficulty-add-link-to-the-rule-here&quot;&gt;5. Aim for 90% difficulty (add link to the rule here)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should try to target 85-90% difficulty for your cards. If you go into Anki stats you can see the difficulty level for your recent usage.
Too easy and you’re probably reviewing too often (and wasting time). Too hard and you’re not learning anything because you don’t have the understanding.
So, you want it to be difficult but not too difficult.
Unfortunately Anki doesn’t tune itself so you have to tune Anki directly.
You can adjust this in the per-deck settings by changing the ease factors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;6-think-long-term&quot;&gt;6. Think long-term&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t give up on cards after you’ve finished a class or other milestone.
The cool thing about spaced repetition is that you can remember the material forever. If you paid money to learn Calculus you might as well keep it. Once you’ve learned it using spaced repetition is mostly about maintenance.
Since you know the material the scheduling will get farther and farther in the future and there won’t be such a massive burden.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;7-use-the-right-card-type&quot;&gt;7. Use the right card type&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should prefer to use question and answer cards.
These are in the form of
Q: What is the capital of California?
A: Sacramento
This would be as opposed to cloze deletion cards like:
[Sacramento] is the capital of California.
In the above the ‘Sacramento’ string is hidden.
Cloze deletion cards might seem easy but they often give away context clues which weakens the entire point of spaced repetition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid border border-secondary&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/MaTlTKG.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;8-use-cloze-deletions-for-languages&quot;&gt;8. Use cloze deletions for languages&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s one main exception for cloze deletion cards - languages (especially in med school)
Cloze can be good to help with grammar and sentence structure. They should NOT replace Q/A cards though.
For a given word you should have the definition and the forward and reverse translation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid border border-secondary&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/G66EqlD.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;9-use-image-occlusion&quot;&gt;9. Use image occlusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another powerful use case of flashcards is image occlusion, especially in med school. 
Image occlusion allows you practice identifying parts of an image by hiding its description.
After all, it would be quite useful to actually be able to identify the spleen during surgery instead of just knowing facts about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid border border-secondary&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/JAo54HZ.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;10-create-related-cards-for-a-360-understanding&quot;&gt;10. Create related cards for a 360 understanding&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re struggling to remember cards because it seems like random facts, add more cards around the topic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, if you want to know who was the first vice president of the US ( John Adams), add a card about who was the second president (surprise surprise - John Adams again). Now it’s much easier to get a better understanding of Adam’s career, not just the random fact that he was the first Vice President.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;11-make-it-absurd-and-fun&quot;&gt;11. Make it absurd and fun&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you were driving to work and you saw a naked man riding a horse on the side of the road would you need to remember it?
Would you have to write it down?
No. It would burn in your mind. You’d remember this image for a decade. Do this for your Anki cards you’re trying to remember.
Below is an example of a ‘fun’ mnemonic device. I’m sure you have all seen more absurd and ridiculous ones, which we’ll abstain from showing here for now…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid border border-secondary&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/YtpRZX7.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;12-create-only-cards-you-actually-plan-to-study&quot;&gt;12. Create only cards you actually plan to study&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t create nonsense cards. Ask yourself if the card will actually help you.
Remember that spaced repetition is an efficient scheduler so going from 5k to 10k cards isn’t 2x more work. It is initially but quickly your spacings increase and you’re going to just be reviewing a few cards per day again.
However, by only keeping important cards in there this helps you avoid card burnout. Reason #1 why people stop using spaced repetition is that the ‘why’ is not there.
The why is because they’re valuable!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;13-use-shingling-to-remember-speeches&quot;&gt;13. Use ‘shingling’ to remember speeches&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do not include entire speeches to remember. Instead. Instead, use overlapping sentences.
For example, if you want to remember the following:
Four score and seven years ago our fathers brought forth on this continent a new nation, conceived in Liberty, and dedicated to the proposition that all men are created equal. Now we are engaged in a great civil war, testing whether that nation or any nation so conceived and so dedicated, can long endure. We are met on a great battle-field of that war. We have come to dedicate a portion of that field, as a final resting place for those who here gave their lives that that nation might live.
Break it out into three cards:
Q: Four score and seven years ago our fathers brought forth on this continent a new nation, conceived in Liberty, and dedicated to the proposition that all men are created equal.
A: Now we are engaged in a great civil war, testing whether that nation or any nation so conceived and so dedicated, can long endure.
–
Q: Now we are engaged in a great civil war, testing whether that nation or any nation so conceived and so dedicated, can long endure.
A: We are met on a great battle-field of that war.
–
Q: We are met on a great battle-field of that war.
A: We have come to dedicate a portion of that field, as a final resting place for those who here gave their lives that that nation might live.
This will help you connect the parts without having to choke on a massive card with the entire speech.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;14-use-extra-fields&quot;&gt;14. Use extra fields&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Create an ‘extra’ field with your cards so that you can add notes and pictures so that when you fail to remember you can get back to the original context.
We’ll often put the book information. The actual text of where I saw the card, etc.
In fact, one of the Polar features we’re working on is to add this directly so when you create a flashcard in Polar it automatically generates a card with the context.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;15-use-stories-and-etymology&quot;&gt;15. Use stories and etymology&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Attach ‘extra’ stories to the material but or use imagery to remember the material.
We’ve found that etymology works VERY well for learning languages.
For example. The German word for sea is Meer which is related to the English word marine and mare (Spanish / Italian for sea).
See, now you’re already speaking three languages ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;16-use-cards-to-remember-faces&quot;&gt;16. Use cards to remember faces&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is one of our favorite hacks. Most people have trouble matching faces and names. 
I used to have an excel file with names and any additional information where I met them. Actually adding the picture makes it 10x more powerful&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;17-and-finally-dont-fall-for-ankiapp&quot;&gt;17. And finally… don’t fall for AnkiApp&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sure you’re using Anki and not AnkiApp&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can read about &lt;a href=&quot;https://getpolarized.io/2020/02/03/anki-ripped-off.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;our research&lt;/a&gt; into it here. Anki is the popular open-source platform used by many. AnkiApp is a Chinese rip-off riding the wave of Anki’s popularity&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid border border-secondary&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/zr9cCga.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are our Anki tips from years of using it hands-on. Use the above tips to keep moving forward with spaced repetition. Use a tool like &lt;a href=&quot;https://getpolarized.io/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Polar&lt;/a&gt; to easily create flashcards and sync them to Anki.
Spaced repetition is tremendously powerful. However, it won’t replace the work of actually understanding the material. This is still your job.
Finally, make sure you’re also using the right Anki plugins and that you’re using it to full effect. You can read more about the most popular Anki add-ons &lt;a href=&quot;https://getpolarized.io/2020/02/14/Must-have-Anki-Add-ons-for-Medical-Students-in-2020.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Top 5 Flashcard Apps for 2020</title><link href="https://getpolarized.io/2020/02/14/Top-Five-Flashcard-Apps-2020.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Top 5 Flashcard Apps for 2020" /><published>2020-02-14T09:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-02-14T09:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://getpolarized.io/2020/02/14/Top-Five-Flashcard-Apps-2020</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://getpolarized.io/2020/02/14/Top-Five-Flashcard-Apps-2020.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid border&quot; src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/iYQT8NIMpLc_INNphQ1PKFUb58tQltgpYoHvi9VAz_poWbGTEWUfP6qZR9ya50bw_4wxC3iq4W0B3k8-PS_l0zzSIjCsT4MoK70x9h7e7eI9IaJaf56tb-bQzo5AnWCWTkou_za1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;top-5-flashcard-apps-for-2020&quot;&gt;Top 5 Flashcard Apps for 2020&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Flashcards have a reputation for being one of the most popular ways of studying and retaining information. They’re also a time-tested tool. Their history dates back to the 19th century when English educator Favell Lee Mortimer used a set of phonics flashcards. Here’s a nice read on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.brainscape.com/blog/2012/04/history-of-flashcards/&quot;&gt;history of flashcards&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since then, flashcards have come a long way and have been adapted for mobile platforms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s quite handy to know how to write good flashcards. You can start by mixing pictures and words — imagery helps you recollect experiences a lot better. This is also known as the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=27CsEELSkrw&quot;&gt;Picture Superiority Effect&lt;/a&gt; in cognitive psychology. You can also try to break complex concepts into multiple simpler questions. Making good flashcards goes a long way in learning and retaining new information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Multiple software and mobile app solutions exist to simplify your life when creating flashcards. There’s a reason for that — flashcards significantly improve your learning experience. But with so many options, choosing the best flashcard app can be quite confusing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make things simpler, here’s our list of top flashcard tools for 2020.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;1-anki&quot;&gt;1. &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.ankiweb.net/&quot;&gt;Anki&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid border&quot; src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/6wCjFqZQ8sYwfSiBaBP7I2rb4_lhHopsAiHFdfCEHc9-funfUZZCAs-plmovAYHdonlun8YVb_df4ozPSppUY5o6o5Gcy_1kVr6KQvurU36vmz_PBYtgjo_GVu5iV2sUg265pCJt&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overview: Anki in Japanese stands for memorization. It’s free and open source, and utilizes spaced retention to increase your memorization. Anki supports all popular platforms such as Windows, macOS, Android, iOS, Linux.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are quite a few handy &lt;a href=&quot;https://ankiweb.net/shared/addons/2.1&quot;&gt;Anki add-ons&lt;/a&gt; that you can download for free and use it to customize Anki as per your needs. These Anki add-ons add numerous customization options to make your learning experience more engaging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For beginners, it might take some time to get used to Anki’s interface. But if you ever feel stuck, you can check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.ankiweb.net/docs/manual.html&quot;&gt;Anki’s manual&lt;/a&gt; which has extensive resources on using the software, making flashcards, and working around them. .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you need a reliable app that comes with great customization, then Anki should be your go-to option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Primary target audience: Medical students&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Integration: Anki add-ons&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pricing: Free for Windows, Mac, Linux and Android; $24.99 for iOS&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;2-polar&quot;&gt;2. &lt;a href=&quot;https://getpolarized.io/&quot;&gt;Polar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid border&quot; src=&quot;https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/yHGvyNl84L4IyDOIZnGsGkmIOEGxGbs_HNJHz-ucg2shHSq2lro01qImL1HHpX605QFdbHnFxPVadvSKBm6E-Xt3WF0IknKxWglDcYVQAUii-lqaJJi6aYQIe-ttG3I0OVEVciAM&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overview: Polar is an all-in-one learning tool which supports a document manager, reader, and learning tools. If you are studying from a PDF or a website (which is becoming more common every day), it’s easy to create flashcards based on what you are reading. Polar allows you to auto-convert annotations into flashcards with one simple button.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Polar also integrates with Anki. Using Polar as an add-on to Anki enables automatic syncing between both tools. Yes, you can take your flashcards on the go with the effective learning duo of Polar and Anki.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, another feature that sets Polar apart from other reading tools is its advanced reader functionality. This includes incremental reading, reading progress tracking, and various other features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Primary target audience: students, universal&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Integration: Can sync with Anki&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pricing: Free; paid plans starting at $4.99 per month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;3-tinycards-by-duolingo&quot;&gt;3. &lt;a href=&quot;https://tinycards.duolingo.com/&quot;&gt;TinyCards by Duolingo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid border&quot; src=&quot;https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/sf0EfevV4Kc4zP39kTKT-lD-vCJkWOM20Z1DXBz0wjMebnX0m2z71bZfVhFoXajoVb5_K2isQddBOty5l4U94qtc6xiQvVAahDC1DVNoKhlXyueO01g-qY3VO9l9Mc0hyHSfZZ2N&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overview: TinyCards is brought to you by Duolingo, your favorite neighborhood language learning app. Wait, what happened to your last Duolingo learning streak? Are you still on? ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, TinyCards mobile app by Duolingo brings spaced retention at the tip of your fingers through flashcards. The best part of TinyCards is its design: it looks quite elegant and has a colorful interface which stands out . Good design is a great motivation to learn new stuff!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can make new lessons, access lessons by other people, and look for lessons. You also have the option to set practice reminders, which is helpful if you want to get some learning done. TinyCards is a great way to fill your time by learning new things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TinyCards is available for the web, Android, iOS, and Google Chrome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Primary target audience: language learners, universal&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Integration: Duolingo&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pricing: Free&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;4-quizlet&quot;&gt;4. &lt;a href=&quot;https://quizlet.com/&quot;&gt;Quizlet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid border&quot; src=&quot;https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/rJXpKl2OPcJM8aYHmmMvw0ctEIw5qxX4LqDDpNtqKBfFlfaeD78X3PNPoXy6qnkgiX_ddaKmT3UASKRDApsZ08Kx7P2T5DZyR2Jv4J55bedmuOarFowP8GqOxGf8AlYvvGUqows5&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overview: Quizlet’s claims that over 90 percent of students who use Quizlet report getting higher grades in their tests. Well, a lot of it is possible due to their flashcard tool. With Quizlet, you can create your own flashcards, revise flashcards made by a classmate, or search the archive of millions of flashcard decks created by students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quizlet also gives you access to an inbuilt image library, which makes integrating images in your flashcards a walk in the park. Once you are done with creating flashcards, you can study them, go back and edit them, and even share them with your friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quizlet is a great way to study with friends. It is available for Windows, Mac, Android and iOS. The app is free to use, but you can purchase plans such as Quizlet Plus and Quizlet Go are available, providing features such as offline access, document scanning, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Primary target audience: High School and college students&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Integration: Quizlet image library&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pricing: Free download and paid upgrades&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;5-cram&quot;&gt;5. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cram.com/&quot;&gt;Cram&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid border&quot; src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/hRGDdEAIxkW7wnsSjUzP8rrStojSJOf1myp1vyNgM8brHj7wKHV8C7PbrHexMr1Pg5WAttvNrpOKME9L7dS_uMXleFzXICWjHt_saWh-cOVKm7lQBvtGPFKxc5eu5UJTftp4uDCV&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overview: Cram makes cramming fun — that’s what they say. It has been around since 2001 and has over 195 million flashcards that you can access any moment. You can also use Cram to create your own online flashcards, export and share them, and even collaborate with others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cram is available for both Android and iOS, so you can have your cards on the go. You also get to create flashcards on the web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Primary target audience: students&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Integration: Developers program&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pricing: Free&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People and developers are finding new ways of using flashcard tools. &lt;a href=&quot;https://thesector.com.au/2020/02/03/a-21st-century-approach-to-emergent-literacy-no-flashcards-in-preschool-please/&quot;&gt;Some are opposing it&lt;/a&gt; as well, especially in playschools, saying that early learning needs to be creative and challenging. Flashcards have nothing against extensive print learning, they’re a proven way of learning new information. Sometimes the new stuff does not have much of a creative approach to it, as in the case of the many medical terminologies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides, flashcards can be fun. The add-ons for Anki have made them more engaging and interactive, where they are more than just binary. Their integrations to document managers such as Polar have also proved how they can be effectively integrated to find more applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, flashcards are particularly powerful when coupled with other learning methods. In particular, association or absurd and ridiculous imagery can help tremendously in retaining information on flashcards.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Must-have Anki Add-ons for Medical Students in 2020</title><link href="https://getpolarized.io/2020/02/14/Must-have-Anki-Add-ons-for-Medical-Students-in-2020.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Must-have Anki Add-ons for Medical Students in 2020" /><published>2020-02-14T09:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-02-14T09:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://getpolarized.io/2020/02/14/Must-have-Anki-Add-ons-for-Medical-Students-in-2020</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://getpolarized.io/2020/02/14/Must-have-Anki-Add-ons-for-Medical-Students-in-2020.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;must-have-anki-add-ons-for-medical-students-in-2020&quot;&gt;Must-have Anki Add-ons for Medical Students in 2020&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all know med school is tough and the amount of information required to memorize is tremendous. So obviously the question begs why not make it easy on yourself and use some powerful tools?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anki is an open source flashcard software. If you’re here, you likely know how popular it is among med school students. Since it’s open source, anyone can build on top of it. So we decided to compile a list of most popular add-ons we heard from &lt;a href=&quot;https://getpolarized.io/&quot;&gt;our users&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid border&quot; src=&quot;https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/knT-rTG6qdw8OlKZUIijJm2_r2d6-tB3_Dop0AouIW9WUmaFCvsSAxL-b1uqpjxppt1ubnVVqwjobPGfU2qaGZpho1w8YEESLBd2OS_c6AXinYz-YBdO97q9nxR--KXLrOec4sq_&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find the free add-ons on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://ankiweb.net/shared/addons/2.1&quot;&gt;Anki website&lt;/a&gt; to improve your Anki experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are hundreds of add-ons by other Anki users. With every Anki update, more functionality is added, especially through support of more add-ons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have categorized these Anki add-ons to make it easy to find what you are looking for. While these Anki add-ons are great for med students, they can be used by other students or casual learners as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid border&quot; src=&quot;https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/hpJLma7qa1jb98a0y_AUdwsW7HCVio2-82yd6FYOj3VbyKU3aYMuT1xZWLDTwBGUJe7kOUio5s-YPoHbUr1WxSbM462fFWj6qHyVswBpK6dI1G71iGRVTk6rRMuMdgK-cbWVcg6v&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To install an Anki add-on, go to the tools menu and then Add-ons, then click on Browse &amp;amp; Install and paste in the code. Here’s also a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=saVJN5-_JDM&quot;&gt;video&lt;/a&gt; that explains this process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that, let’s get started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;gamification&quot;&gt;Gamification&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These add-ons will bring some fun to your learning habits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;pokemanki&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ankiweb.net/shared/info/633922407&quot;&gt;Pokemanki&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Updates: Regular&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Popularity: Very popular (73 upvotes)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid border&quot; src=&quot;https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/L5L0Y_E3KJaKH0lqSIAsuPjzSZcZ1uNQALd0acl2jfzTPix3eyMWnHUkVqK4WV1ikpm9PFtayuzU79hMqe8StjORlwq4ITPxQuI7gtzoKo1LSDpBfQBzkkdsfoi-qB5QGQ4DM4dK&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Description: The Pokemanki add-on will keep you motivated to use Anki by letting you catch and train Pokemons inside your deck. It gives you a hatchable Pokemon egg for each lowest-level deck that you start learning. Your Pokemon will keep on leveling up as you review and learn the cards in the deck. They might even evolve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can access your Pokemons under your Stats screen. They will be above all your figures and charts. You will be able to see Pokemons for specific decks and their origin. Just review the deck to keep on training them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anki code: 633922407&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;kitten-rewards&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ankiweb.net/shared/info/1627107763&quot;&gt;Kitten Rewards&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Updates: Infrequent&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Popularity: Somewhat popular (15 upvotes)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid border&quot; src=&quot;https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/CKiNmo5xYzaNQK9IhKJkdjopDZdzsZchuDQ6kAVnGFMOXee_IlSaxJLLkej04ayeX4KdmW6fWI3B3PHIPeq39g9ljOh7hPgVRMSslG2sYl4ww5nWl_U9JvgdB3aakP1T6Qs9wB2U&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Description: Kittens rule the internet, and they have taken over Anki decks as well. Kitten Rewards is an Anki add-on which acts as an excellent learning motivator. This add-on has a simple concept: it adds a “cute kitten” on the congrats screen after a deck is finished. So if you lack motivation to study, use this add-on to get back on track.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s more? You can upload your own kitten pictures as well :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anki code: 1627107763&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;anki-fanfare&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ankiweb.net/shared/info/2073603704&quot;&gt;Anki Fanfare&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Updates: Infrequent&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Popularity: Somewhat popular (14 upvotes)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid border&quot; src=&quot;https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/tuwlhIAeqgQ6Ac5ETqPd0ROFwiMGhmwY7TtdcmVJcsu644YOWfit65PG0dRX37frgg8ZMHm_X2AFGaryy9VuS4n2hqgtYOTFrq1yHByqGetQzr1IgaJTzuOLKNLOuFQk9rFqJ9C2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Description: Anki fanfare is another cool add-on if you want to add a particular theme to your flashcard review. For example, there’s a trout theme and a Bruce Lee theme. The trout theme shows pictures of trout, and the Bruce Lee theme shows you sayings from the Master. Be like water?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has so many themes that you can use with your cards. Simply download a particular theme and unzip it to “fanfare/user_files”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Users have reviewed this add-on writing that they get a “dopamine hit” every time they finish a card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anki code: 2073603704&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;anki-habitat&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ankiweb.net/shared/info/1758045507&quot;&gt;Anki Habitat&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Updates: Regular&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Popularity: Somewhat popular (14 upvotes)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid border&quot; src=&quot;https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/b4EjFuoozRUGQWkFosKcvOLyeofphP_ICvhpug_iH-etso4MSvMqI0eA_UF0QNw2M9Zq64eq0QX640HbiS6tW81qHnjeOFKxTW-J9SUJY9CzJMQp48IbNqgVXxsq5W20HmwBF0zA&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Description: A little RPG magic always does the trick. No, we are not talking about Skyrim — you might never do any learning around Skyrim. But this little RPG integrated into the Anki software can take you a long way when it comes to finding a little motivation while reviewing those cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anki Habitat is supported across platforms. It works by adding points to your &lt;a href=&quot;https://habitica.com/static/home&quot;&gt;Habitica stats&lt;/a&gt; as you progress through your cards. With these points added to your Habitica character, you can battle your friends and slay monsters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a really cool add-on if you already use Habitica. If not, give it a try and motivate yourself to achieve your goals. Over 2,000,000 people are having fun through Habitica while achieving their goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anki code: 1758045507&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;productivity&quot;&gt;Productivity&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some Anki plugins to boost your productivity and ace your card review.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;polar-connect---pdf-and-incremental-reading-with-anki-sync&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ankiweb.net/shared/info/734898866&quot;&gt;Polar Connect - PDF and Incremental Reading with Anki Sync&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Updates: Regular&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Popularity: Very popular (45 upvotes)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid border&quot; src=&quot;https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/zrCPs4Gs0jX_G85QQ-oE7WXIWlEdlFrh2joxpDEW3_c_T5wubbt1V7SxvYPmJ5uKAwM0zoCRubcdqnl5Fw-DcsYAXDS5llHar7u2iAlOSonxWFNX91EK6ESlrFev74K6VIq5cBRa&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Description: &lt;a href=&quot;https://getpolarized.io/&quot;&gt;Polar&lt;/a&gt; is a document manager, reader, and learning tool all in one. Have you ever had to study from a book or a website and then create flashcards based on what you’re reading? Well, Polar is your tool. With Polar, you can auto-convert any annotation, highlight, or comment in one click into a flashcard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Polar add-on for Anki establishes a communication channel between Polar and Anki to easily sync flashcards from Polar to Anki.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, Polar simplifies managing a reading list with tags, groups, reading progress tracking, and more&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anki code: 734898866&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;more-overview-stats&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ankiweb.net/shared/info/2116130837&quot;&gt;More Overview Stats&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Updates: Infrequent&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Popularity: Popular (38 upvotes)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid border&quot; src=&quot;https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/Cnu5SDauGvu2J0ngVM8ym-_K5IMkL4ZRvWI4OJ_FJJaiodtFpocf5Fg6ZEvb2WVkiWvvGlDoDMxE2-K_cUzRC2ZEGz_PCwto5QZ0BIKUVDvWh81yZ3lW6mMWOGm3hGO_8D2cIYrh&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Description: As the name indicates, this Anki plugin adds more stats to your overview page. This way you can keep track of your learning progress. It even adds colors to the labels for a different touch to the Anki stats page. When you hover over the colors, they show you the cards in the following order: new, learn, review, buried, and suspended.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anki code: 2116130837&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;batch-editing&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ankiweb.net/shared/info/291119185&quot;&gt;Batch Editing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Updates: Regular&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Popularity: Popular (66 upvotes)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid border&quot; src=&quot;https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/2-dtmZqtpQC2YRTrLSUtqBlWSy_sQNVPhRd10F7Jkm9qImc1WhO9_e5OZ8L5KTFesFI9w7PRHFR0BSIi8eIv_nHiJHikrQWNxpp3Zzm5TTsOA7PeAxAcJYSkXB3R_8Uj89_Vesq1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Description: The Batch Editing add-on for Anki adds a new menu item to the card browser, which allows you to do two things: Batch-add information/media to a specific field, batch-replace the contents of any particular field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The changes that you make are applied to all selected notes that are featured in the field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iCZzcSnAeH4&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be&quot;&gt;instructional video&lt;/a&gt; on how to use this add-on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anki code: 291119185&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;visual-upgrades&quot;&gt;Visual upgrades&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visual upgrades to Anki enhance the way it looks, giving it room for more memory cues and helping you learn faster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;night-mode&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ankiweb.net/shared/info/1496166067&quot;&gt;Night Mode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Updates: Regular&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Popularity: Very popular (383 upvotes - I mean, seriously, who doesn’t love night mode?)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid border&quot; src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/A0CvRPNWwemX65-lcw-n-_yQfzbqcTkXkctPInMNtuHDcAP2lMqBuqHAsV0uo3SbX0H_uOASDu90eF6LEB1uchgvVydUzU3OehpHv2SdzF8Avo0nOcMtLo4DwfV9neLJvkgOid1a&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Description: The history of night modes can be traced back to Windows Phone 7. The feature was added to the now-dead OS to reduce battery consumption as entirely black pixels didn’t emit any light on OLED screens. Since then, night mode as a feature in apps and software has come a long way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s one the best Anki add-ons for medical students as they can recharge their deck review (even at night) by modifying Anki to having an all-black background. The add-on gives you the option to automatically (timer) or manually turn on the night mode. You can even invert colors of images or latex formulas and define custom color substitution rules.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anki code: 1496166067&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;button-colors&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ankiweb.net/shared/info/2494384865&quot;&gt;Button Colors&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Updates: Infrequent&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Popularity: Very popular (111 upvotes)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid border&quot; src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-WY26FUE2TLF8zif4Po9ifD--XFHyOxGbGi0Ga2KkNRk8gXA1Hl0UxX2Zu5arx4ghjD-BQA7YzVKYq_b8R3szTrSV9uW1-bxFPswSFVDDrJjX_86sUK0WOwK2ACVRZNcDe5QgX9z&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Description: If you need some rigorous learning done through Anki, then you might as well use some colors. You must know that the Anki’s deck page has buttons defined as ‘Good’, ‘Easy’, and ‘Again’ to update the time between iterations on a card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This add-on only imitates the impact of colors on humans: red is known to pose a bit of danger, and you are good to go when things are green. This add-on makes the “Good” button green and the “Again” button red.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’m a simple man. I see colours, I click like.” — add-on review.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anki code: 2494384865&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;full-screen-toggle&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ankiweb.net/shared/info/1612375712&quot;&gt;Full Screen Toggle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Updates: Infrequent&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Popularity: Somewhat popular (14 upvotes)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid border&quot; src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/a9MN67reec94gRuVkAjEloL2wlSssF2ODWIzRGsgIYhwElz4qx0ubA_N710OYrX1Lf70qwbC7gjT7zj70A08UpFucN2fB6PQ05_4H7Ixksq5U2R6FRVUNq_6Gly49xexc6wb2uhV&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Description: Medical studies require a high amount of focus. There are so many new terms coming in, and you wouldn’t want to entertain any distractions as you try to get through them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This add-on does what it says — it adds F11 key binding so that you can toggle full screen on Anki. You can also find this feature in the Tools menu. With this add-on at hand, you can cast all the distractions aside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anki code: 1612375712&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;customize-keyboard-shortcuts&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ankiweb.net/shared/info/24411424&quot;&gt;Customize Keyboard Shortcuts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Updates: Frequent&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Popularity: Popular (44 upvotes)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid border&quot; src=&quot;https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/T6S-VKMuCjgB6I5Wbr_KFRfTMVN223ofUDbu0NOtQP4FsvKopRS_gcW3VLZLcJhugYySebj2xhEH8WTZXOfMHmF8lpschKJA5hFSsfCQIWW_yxMnKiAc6fMmAmjs5tXI12lsantD&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Description: The Keyboards Shortcuts add-on is designed to increase your efficiency on the Anki app. It allows you to change the shortcuts on the main page, the editor window, the review window, and the deck browser window.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can head over to Tools &amp;gt; Add-ons&amp;gt; Custom Shortcuts and click Config to change each shortcut inside Anki.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anki code: 24411424&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;usability&quot;&gt;Usability&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The add-ons under this category add extra features to the way you use Anki. With these add-ons in action, you can do much more than just reviewing your deck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;imageresizer&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ankiweb.net/shared/info/1214357311&quot;&gt;ImageResizer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Updates: Infrequent&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Popularity: Popular (67 upvotes)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid border&quot; src=&quot;https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/9ZSYQY0K7qHtww0eAs4Z7y1Bs07sTiRCyWLqCIQUuiu6D6EADMdseC30il9RRKjejdi7hwPEangHAKEuPtWC5RycMuc0yzqvjacQ_j8tMUb38QDzHdo3xPwh6xkYHjKXvstt18Pz&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Description: The whole point of Anki is to make memorization more efficient. Now imagine this: you plan out your cards, add images, and at the review time, you realize that the pictures are too small or big.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the ImageResizer add-on, you can resize all the images to the desired format and make sure that the image size is not a problem anymore. To change the shortcut and the size of the photos you are using, click on Tools, and then go to ImageResizer. The add-on page has a great tutorial to figure out exactly how to use this add-on to your advantage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anki code: 1214357311&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;image-occlusion-enhanced&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ankiweb.net/shared/info/1374772155&quot;&gt;Image Occlusion Enhanced&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Updates: Frequent&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Popularity: Very popular (159 upvotes)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid border&quot; src=&quot;https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/wDyGKjRLb-4Zo3oUPTWCfS_NnmPyY222p0mHQdq6M-hechRcIP-Skl5m_DI7oQfhw3LZg752gqzSk8RCBcaqmlqfuQthHn4VXpmQihEiidNm9Vm8v2s3-ZcZfXD7lfKIAvFolbL0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Description: Have you ever had to remember body parts from an image? Probably… :) A quick and effective way to remember these names is by hiding parts of an image in your card and then testing your knowledge of that hidden information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Occlusion Enhanced Addon is designed to do just that. You can use it to memorize things better by hiding labels in a diagram, and then revealing them. The cards generated under this add-on are described as ‘mage-based cloze-deletions’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s even a series of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PL3MozITKTz5YFHDGB19ypxcYfJ1ITk_6o&quot;&gt;video tutorials&lt;/a&gt; on how to use the add-on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anki code: 1374772155&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;awesometts&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ankiweb.net/shared/info/427598962&quot;&gt;AwesomeTTS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Updates: Infrequent&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Popularity: Popular (74 upvotes)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid border&quot; src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/e155vNGq_2j0WbHpNjPqNCyCJ8jFCab2YJBnSIb8q-FSQ-HfH3Jf7zoTYFJJyy2NclBx_a1axJEQ03MogAL2o9z6bJOr25X1MVs4osuYhXCwK_tJ_LhB2mnhSq_YzZkjU8_gDA2t&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Description: The AwesomeTTS add-on makes it easier for medical students to learn new terms by adding speed to their card decks. It has the option to store MP3 or speech to the collection. And yes, you can generate MP3 files on the go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ankiatts.appspot.com/&quot;&gt;Click here&lt;/a&gt; to find their documentation, including their usage, service, and configuration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anki code: 427598962&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;batch-download-pictures-from-google-images&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ankiweb.net/shared/info/561924305&quot;&gt;Batch Download Pictures From Google Images&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Updates: Frequent&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Popularity: Somewhat popular (10 upvotes)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid border&quot; src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-yGhpw99WW_-etv8GzdmL2IxOoAP4aCQ2lAhdqrUlpTKitjrLZrkkp9xW-_nN4H2bRoXzTFahp4z-5dKARpWWQgCxllTVgwUN68YcTYILeNRhfwlI2xWOgjnoHWQ-wG9l_OY1cfq&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Description: Wouldn’t it be great if you can batch download pictures to Anki through an add-on so that you can later use them in your cards? This add-on for Anki downloads pictures from Google Images into a destination field. You also get to select how many pictures to download and choose the maximum height and width for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The add-on is fast and takes about 3 seconds to download a picture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anki code: 561924305&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;web-browser---search-terms-import-texts-and-images-automatically&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ankiweb.net/shared/info/864545277&quot;&gt;Web Browser - Search terms, Import texts and images automatically&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Updates: Regular&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Popularity: Somewhat popular (24 upvotes)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid border&quot; src=&quot;https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/I4XACvOahc_-G7YCHC-Lm6z4kdLpomwuFYjJvRjnLqIy2TWX8L4nViLtzzJfYRl9XVLUe7haEli2yOceJzkkqrm_u88av6NGiJeAkHdvnjHyTei0WHbhfhPRZe2H4YzfgMPAjWHJ&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Description: Web browsers can be a distraction. You sit with Anki open on your computer, and next thing you know, you are browsing memes on Reddit ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This add-on prevents you from opening your computer’s web browser by installing a native browser to Anki. It has a simple browser that lets you search words on the internet and then later import the information to your card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anki code: 864545277&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;review-heatmap&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/glutanimate/review-heatmap/releases&quot;&gt;Review Heatmap&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Updates: Regular&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Popularity: Popular (50 upvotes)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid border&quot; src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/hj9JzYZq7zIULpVaxRMoUSQ11CQbPuOYnYb4EcJ8mfGhDzembP2Fj2Fof4mr-_7hSpBb-b_fboYGDIYFRQJ71hB0H1eEQIXp_aD7a1IkGakY4tEjQDIn2FVfzyPxgNSvXyKfTm-8&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Description: While studying, it’s always great to track your progress. Anki does come with some stats that you can look at, but the Review Heatmap add-on gives you an advanced tracking functionality. It’s a great Anki plugin for med students as it shows you your daily review averages, days learned, current streak, and longest streak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The newest release for Anki 2.1 is still in Beta, and you can download it from &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/glutanimate/review-heatmap/releases&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. This Anki plugin also integrates well with the Night Mode add-on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anki code: Suggested download from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/glutanimate/review-heatmap/releases/tag/v0.7.0-beta.1&quot;&gt;beta page on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Summary&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here you have it folks. These Anki add-ons for medical students can save you valuable time and totally redefine the way you use Anki to learn and retain new information. Most of these plugins come with great support and documentation to make their usage as easy as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have other add-ons you think med students should use, do let us know.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Must-have Anki Add-ons for Medical Students in 2020</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Polar 1.90.18 - Stability Improvements and Auto Pagemarks</title><link href="https://getpolarized.io/2020/02/07/Polar-1-90-18-Stability-And-Auto-Pagemarks.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Polar 1.90.18 - Stability Improvements and Auto Pagemarks" /><published>2020-02-07T09:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-02-07T09:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://getpolarized.io/2020/02/07/Polar-1-90-18-Stability-And-Auto-Pagemarks</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://getpolarized.io/2020/02/07/Polar-1-90-18-Stability-And-Auto-Pagemarks.html">&lt;p&gt;Polar 1.90.18 is now available for all desktop users and will be rolling out over the next week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;stability&quot;&gt;Stability&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A ton of work has gone into stability to continue improving reliability for users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;filtering-annotations-in-sidebar&quot;&gt;Filtering Annotations in Sidebar&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can now filter annotations in the sidebar to search by text.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/Ph4xcM7.png&quot; class=&quot;border&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;auto-pagemarks&quot;&gt;Auto Pagemarks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have preview support for auto-pagemarks which are part of our new &lt;a href=&quot;https://getpolarized.io/docs/new-pagemark-design.html&quot;&gt;pagemark design&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will create pagemarks automatically while you naturally read the document.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have to enable it in settings (as it’s preview for now) and it only supports PDF documents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re going to probably make this the default mode and remove manually sized pagemark boxes as this is a better initial
user experience but also resolves some issues with manually resized pagemarks being buggy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;full-changelog&quot;&gt;Full Changelog&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.90.18&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sentry is now disabled as it was breaking windows builds.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Flow for the annotation sidebar now fixes the header at the top and 
properly sets overflow so just the sidebar text flows.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Short term workaround for a bug where firebase won’t write to prefs on 
startup which blocked cloud sync on restart for some users.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Upgraded to latest Firebase libraries (7.7.0)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixed bug with spacing in the tree sidebar for nodes that get compressed.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ability to filter annotations on the sidebar.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixed bug with performing reviews when nothing left was available.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixed bug with #? not being encoded properly due when creating file URLs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Polar 1.90.18 is now available for all desktop users and will be rolling out over the next week.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Decentralized social media using federated and peer-to-peer protocols</title><link href="https://getpolarized.io/2020/02/04/decentralized-social-media.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Decentralized social media using federated and peer-to-peer protocols" /><published>2020-02-04T09:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-02-04T09:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://getpolarized.io/2020/02/04/decentralized-social-media</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://getpolarized.io/2020/02/04/decentralized-social-media.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;decentralized-social-media-using-federated-and-peer-to-peer-protocols&quot;&gt;Decentralized social media using federated and peer-to-peer protocols&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following overview is loosely based on a presentation by Jay Graber at the Internet Archive in San Francisco on Jan 21, 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/BaJJyCJ.png&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Presentation at Internet Archive on decentralized social media&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given the impact social media has had on our lives in the last few years - from less privacy to election interfering - an increasing focus has been put on decentralized social media platforms as a potential solution. In addition, the crypto boom of 2017 brought blockchain to the mainstream media, which further helped out projects in that space&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While these platforms promise a better solution to existing social media, no single platform has to date achieved the kind of success seen in the early stages of Facebook, Twitter, Reddit, and others. In fact, not only do many face technical challenges and delays, the business model is oftentimes not clear either&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Decentralized social media platforms are primarily built on two types of protocols - federated protocols or peer-to-peer protocols&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;federated-protocols&quot;&gt;Federated protocols&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A federated protocol allows multiple small networks to talk to each other without giving away too much control&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Examples of platforms using such a protocol include ActivityPub built on Mastodon. ActivityPub is a social network with nearly about 2.2M users and roughly doubled its user base in 2019
Matrix is a chat platform and another example using a federated protocol with ~11M users. Matrix allows multiple communication platforms to all integrate into one&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid border&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/PCUysdj.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;ActivityPub's landing page&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid border&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/91LoKlw.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Matrix' approach to decentralized communication&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main advantages of federated protocols are a familiar UX, no user key management, and control of moderation policy by the user. Generally speaking, platforms using federated protocols are closer to what we are used to seeing in social media. For example, they allow for users to change and delete content&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key disadvantages are a stronger dependence on admins, identities being potentially bound to specific servers, and platforms can lack privacy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;peer-to-peer-protocols&quot;&gt;Peer-to-peer protocols&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a peer-to-peer protocol, no distinction is made between a client and a server, meaning all nodes are equal&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most well-known example of such a protocol is scuttlebutt. Scuttlebutt is a protocol for gossip sharing with an estimated 16k nodes. Social media platforms built on it include Patchwork, Manyverse, and Planetary&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid border&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/chXxdT4.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Manyverse - a social network based on a scuttlebutt's peer-to-peer protocol&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In peer-to-peer protocols, users are identified by public keys or human-readable usernames. Moderation is typically achieved bottoms-up which provides a lot of flexibility on which kind of content and under what rules they want to engage with&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additional networks using a peer-to-peer network, though not built on scuttlebutt, are Aether (a Reddit-style network) and Iris (an ethereum-based network)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key advantages of peer-to-peer protocols are the fact that users are able to control their data and identity, capacity scales with demand (since every node is equal), and a local-first approach&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the flipside, peer-to-peer protocols have a few disadvantages as well. Namely, no password recovery, a resource-intensive approach (all data is stored on users’ nodes), and an unfamiliar UX (no deletion, changing of content, no cross-device usage,…). In particular the relatively user-unfriendly features give the peer-to-peer protocols a distinct disadvantage over federated protocols in the social media space&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, a big issue for such protocols is the lack of a clear monetization strategy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-blockchain-is-used-in-the-design&quot;&gt;How blockchain is used in the design&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blockchain is used in two parts of the design - data storage and monetization / payments&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Data can be irreversible stored on a blockchain. Cryptocurrencies built on top of the blockchain protocol are oftentimes employed for monetization of the platform and payments between users&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a few examples that store data on the blockchain AND utilize the blockchain for payments. The best-known example is Steem. Steem is a Reddit-style platform. In addition, the Steem blockchain protocol is being used to build a host of other social media and content sharing platforms&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Examples of platforms that only use blockchain infrastructure for payments include DTube and Minds. DTube is a perfect example of the limitations of blockchain-based content platforms. DTube, a blockchain-based Youtube competitor, requires a huge amount of data to be stored, which makes it practically impossible to use blockchain&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Advantages of blockchain-based social media platforms include decentralized monetization and payments, and decentralized global consensus on identities&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, such platforms also come with significant disadvantages. Namely, key management issues with potential of financial loss, non-modifiable on-chain data, and publicly visible on-chain data. In particular, the last point is contentious among privacy-centric users&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, at the current state of blockchain, the base-layer blockchain is not scalable, though research is actively going on to resolve this problem&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In summary, decentralized social media platforms have not been able to break into the mainstream at the pace traditional ones were able to. It remains to be seen if further privacy violations, data misuse, and other topics will ultimately lead to large-scale adoption&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Decentralized social media using federated and peer-to-peer protocols</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">AnkiApp is Ripping Off Anki</title><link href="https://getpolarized.io/2020/02/03/anki-ripped-off.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="AnkiApp is Ripping Off Anki" /><published>2020-02-03T09:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-02-03T09:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://getpolarized.io/2020/02/03/anki-ripped-off</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://getpolarized.io/2020/02/03/anki-ripped-off.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/s3hmhWJ.png&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;ankiapp-is-ripping-off-anki&quot;&gt;AnkiApp is Ripping Off Anki&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Friday, Redditor u/farazyashar launched a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/Anki/comments/ewoir7/trademark_lawsuit_against_ankiapp/&quot;&gt;discussion&lt;/a&gt; in the Anki subreddit about a potential lawsuit against AnkiApp (Admium). The main rationale behind it is a potential infringement on the name Anki and clear confusion between Anki and AnkiApp (Admium)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, it seems like many AnkiApp (Admium) users had not been aware they are not using the original software and expressed outrage. It’s likely the confusion stemmed from the similar naming of the newer product, with a few Redditors insinuating malicious behavior on Admium’s part&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the following, we clarify any potential confusion and also share a little our own research we conducted into AnkiApp (Admium)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s start with the most important part: how to differentiate between Anki and AnkiApp (Admium)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.ankiweb.net/&quot;&gt;Anki&lt;/a&gt; is a flashcard tool incorporating a simple yet powerful spaced repetition algorithm at its backend. AnkiApp (Admium) is essentially the same tool copied but developed by a corporation called &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.admium.net/&quot;&gt;Admium&lt;/a&gt;, though many reviews point to major issues, such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.ankiapp.client&quot;&gt;regular crashes and data loss&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Key differences include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Design: the original Anki has a very simplistic design. The newer AnkiApp (Admium) has a more elaborate design, though reading their reviews, it suffers from many glitches&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Open-source: the original Anki app is open source. AnkiApp (Admium) is not&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Integration with other apps: the original Anki has many integrations, such as the relatively new Pokamanki add-on or Polar. AnkiApp (Admium) has no integrations that we could find. It only allows you to mass import data from spreadsheets&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Community: the original Anki has a huge community, especially on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/Anki/&quot;&gt;Reddit&lt;/a&gt;. Our research found that the AnkiApp community indeed has its own &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/AnkiApp/&quot;&gt;Subreddit&lt;/a&gt;. As of January 31, 2020, that Subreddit had one user. Several Redditors did point out however, that they initially confused the Anki community with the AnkiApp (Admium) community&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cost: both Anki and AnkiApp (Admium) are free on the Google Play Store and $24.99 on the Apple Store&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/whKsXND.png&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid border&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Anki vs AnkiApp design&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/VjYVKV7.png&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid border&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Anki add-ons&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In summary, it can be confusing for a new user trying to differentiate between both apps. The good news is that the original Anki app appears first when googling and has a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Anki_(software)&quot;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt; article about it under the Anki name&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since we found this topic interesting and confusing at the same time, we decided to dig deeper. Below you’ll find additional findings. It should be clarified from the get-go that there are multiple spaced repetition apps that are using the term Anki, as even specified in AnkiApp’s (Admium) &lt;a href=&quot;https://ankiapp.freshdesk.com/support/solutions/articles/5000359829-is-ankiapp-the-same-as-anki-&quot;&gt;FAQs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;additional-findings-about-ankiapp-admium&quot;&gt;Additional findings about AnkiApp (Admium)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When looking at AnkiApp’s (Admium) website, you notice that Chinese is referenced everywhere. Even on Admium’s website, all text is in English with a few Chinese snippets. It does make you wonder why…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/KmUTdA1.png&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid border&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Admium's website&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since data handling and privacy is a major concern (in particular in the open-source community), we decided to take a
closer look here as well. When looking at AnkiApp’s (Admium) privacy policy, we immediately noticed a lack of
specificity. For once, it is extremely short. Compare AnkiApp’s (Admium) privacy policy to Yelp’s for example. Secondly,
AnkiApp (Admium) fails to clarify how and in which location (US, China, or elsewhere) personal information is being
stored.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems possible that AnkiApp (Admium) is a Chinese-owned company based on the original Anki platform, intended to take
advantage of the confusion in naming. This conclusion is based on the confusion in names as well as Chinese being the
only other supported language used on AnkiApp (Admium). While AnkiApp (Admium) does claim that additional language
support is planned, this claim has been &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20131230030458/http://www.ankiapp.com/&quot;&gt;on the site since early 2014&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, the AnkiApp’s Subreddit’s only user and moderator &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/user/admium/&quot;&gt;u/admium&lt;/a&gt;, only wrote three responses on Reddit, two of which
directly aim at getting Anki users to switch to AnkiApp which further supports the above conclusion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We reached out to AnkiApp (Admium) by phone for clarification, however, did not receive a response. We will keep you
posted if we learn anything new.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Spaced Repetition is Supervised Learning for Humans</title><link href="https://getpolarized.io/2020/01/21/spaced-repetition-is-supervised-learning-for-humans.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Spaced Repetition is Supervised Learning for Humans" /><published>2020-01-21T09:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-01-21T09:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://getpolarized.io/2020/01/21/spaced-repetition-is-supervised-learning-for-humans</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://getpolarized.io/2020/01/21/spaced-repetition-is-supervised-learning-for-humans.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;spaced-repetition-is-supervised-learning-for-humans&quot;&gt;Spaced Repetition is Supervised Learning for Humans&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What if you could train your brain the way computer scientists train computers
and effectively remember anything you want - forever?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the surface this sounds rather absurd. You’re not a computer.  You can’t be
&lt;em&gt;forced&lt;/em&gt; to learn new things.  Education is complicated, and (if you’re like me),
there doesn’t seem to be any rhyme or reason to why some facts stick while you fail
to grasp other (often more complicated) concepts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cognitive science has actually found a way to solve this problem.  It turns out
that we’ve had a solution for more than 135 years and the tools are finally
starting to become mainstream.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This connection between supervised learning (AKA machine learning) and spaced
repetition was my motivation for building Polar. I wanted a unified learning
platform that exploited spaced repetition and made it easy to use and
incorporate into your workflow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll get to the connection between spaced repetition and supervised learning in
a moment but it’s probably best to first explain spaced repetition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;background-in-learning&quot;&gt;Background in Learning&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spaced repetition is centered around what’s known as the ‘forgetting curve’ and
directly exploits the way the brain encodes knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The forgetting curve is based on the intuition that it’s best to study something
&lt;em&gt;just&lt;/em&gt; before it’s forgotten.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/jOAqCpi.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was discovered in 1885 by
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hermann_Ebbinghaus&quot;&gt;Hermann_Ebbinghaus&lt;/a&gt; when he
was researching the rate of information loss when trying to memorize three
letter syllables.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an aside, Ebbinghaus’s major innovation, in my opinion was the use of data
and statistics to learn how the brain functioned internally. Prior to
Ebbinghaus, most “research” on memory was done by philosophers without any form
of scientific rigor (at least no where near Ebbinghaus).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It might be best to think of these as time intervals from when you originally
studied a piece of information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s say you wanted to remember that “Fe is the chemical symbol for Iron.” 
This is actually a bit complicated (at least for English speakers) as Fe is
taken from the Latin word for iron - ferrum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can imagine that this would be quickly forgotten so you might want to recall
it twenty minutes before it’s forgotten.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s this observation that the intervals keep increasing which makes spaced
repetition so powerful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Typical intervals her would involve reviewing the material at 20 minutes, 1
hour, 4hour, 8hour, etc intervals.  These would keep increasing exponentially
until you’re reviewing the material with intervals of years, not minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is eventually a scheduling system to supervise your brain to learn
complicated topics which your brain wouldn’t normally be able to encode. 
Supervised learning for humans.  It’s almost a &lt;em&gt;cognitive prosthetic&lt;/em&gt; designed
for force you to learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;exponential-backoff&quot;&gt;Exponential Backoff&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One key innovation is that spaced repetition intervals use exponential backoff -
or ever increasing intervals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What the heck is exponential backoff?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A naive (and rather insane) strategy to review your flashcards would be to just
review them ever week.  However, This won’t scale to a large number of
flashcards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over ten years, and 15 seconds pre review, this would require 2 hours of study
time - for one card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, using an efficient flashcard scheduler, which adapts itself your
answers, we’re able to retain this knowledge using just 8 iterations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is approximately 99% more efficient (8 * 15 seconds vs more than 2 hours)
than a naive solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These scheduler increases the interval based on your feedback.  If you keep
answering the flashcard properly the interval will increase exponentially
(approximately t^1.3).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, 3 days, then 9 days, then 27, then 81 days, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;##&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s key about the forgetting curve is that it exploits exponential decay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;include a chart of the learning curve&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Hacks to Remember&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Ubsurdity&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Passion&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Bitrot…&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;It’s easier to commit to learning something if you know it will never be forgotten&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What is Machine Learning?&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;unsupervised is where the algorithm, inherently knows what to do and 
generally tends to do the right thing.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;supervised learning is training a computer&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What is Supervised Learning?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Cognitive prosthetic&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Other Mnemonic Strategies
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;these can accelerate spaced repetition but (in my opinion) are not a replacement for SR.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mainstream.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Spaced Repetition is Supervised Learning for Humans</summary></entry></feed>